<Chapter chapter="3" title="Isaiah clearly prophesied Jesus Christ’s sacrifice">

<Paragraph>
The last part of Chapter 52 of Isaiah forms part of the same theme that appears in Chapter 53 which is what in that moment was the future atoning sacrifice of Jesus Christ, the true Lamb of God. From 52:13 forward, the prophet is clearly speaking of the Chosen One of God.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 52:13-15">
<Verse verse="13">
Behold, <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">my servant</P> shall deal prudently, he shall be exalted and extolled, and be very high.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="14">
As many were astonied at thee;
<P ss="1" b="1">his visage was so marred more than any man</P>
, and his form more than the sons of men.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="15">
<P b="1">So shall he sprinkle many nations</P>
; the kings shall shut their mouths at him; for that which had not been told them shall they see; and that which they had not heard shall they consider.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
In verse 52:14 it is understood that we should not expect that the Messiah would be a great general, a political leader or human style strongman, because the prophet says: “His visage was marred more than any man and His form more than the sons of men.” This is why many Jews rejected Him at that time. They wanted a devastatingly strong leader, a victorious general, not a simple carpenter who had come to “sprinkle many nations” with His atoning blood as seen in 52:15. When this verse speaks of nations, it means gentiles.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Jesus perfectly fulfills what is written in 53:1-3 where it is stated that He is to be “despised and rejected” by the people of Israel who hid their faces from Him.
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">It is clear that not all of the people of Israel rejected Christ.</P>
We should remember that at the beginning, the Christian Church was formed exclusively by Jews. These Jews were persecuted and killed by other Jews who did not want to admit that Jesus Christ was the Passover Lamb, the Lamb of God. The Lamb that, like in the Temple sacrifices, took away the sins of those who had faith in His sacrifice. These were Jews that did not want to receive Jesus as the Messiah and persecuted their brothers.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 53:1-3">
<Verse verse="1">
Who hath believed our report? And to whom is the arm of the LORD revealed?
</Verse>

<Verse verse="2">
For he shall grow up before him as a tender plant, and as a root out of a dry ground. He hath no form nor comeliness; and when
<P ss="1" b="1">we shall see him, there is no beauty that we should desire him.</P>
</Verse>

<Verse verse="3">
<P b="1" u="1">He is despised and reiected of men; a man of sorrows, and acquainted with grief</P>
<P b="1">; and</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">we hid as it were our faces</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">from him; he was despised, and we esteemed him not.</P>
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
As can be seen by what we have read, it was prophesied that the God’s Chosen One would be despised by the people of Israel.
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">What other person of messianic stature has been unanimously rejected by the people of Israel?</P>
Doesn’t this general rejection and contempt indicate that Jesus is the Messiah who fulfilled this Isaiah’s prophecy during His first coming? Who else has fulfilled all that this passage says?
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">If only Jesus fulfills all of this, doesn’t this indicate that only Jesus is the Messiah that Isaiah announced?</P>
Why reject Him when after the event we understand how this prophecy was fulfilled in reality?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">Verses 4-6 clearly indicate</P> what the work of the Messiah was to be:
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">But he was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities</P>.
Then the verses clarify that
<P ss="1" b="1">the LORD hath laid on him</P>, (just as in the case of the sacrificial lambs),
<P ss="1" b="1">the iniquity of us all</P>.
How could the prophecy more clearly indicate that the Chosen One of God, the Messiah, came to suffer during His first coming so as to carry away the sins of all of us? Of what other person with messianic stature could you think did fulfill this except only Jesus?
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 53:4-7">
<Verse verse="4">
Surely he hath borne our griefs, and carried our sorrows; yet we did esteem him stricken, smitten of God, and afflicted.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="5">
<P b="1" u="1">But he was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities; the chastisement of our peace was upon him</P>
<P b="1">; and</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">with his stripes we are healed.</P>
</Verse>

<Verse verse="6">
All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the LORD hath laid on him the iniquity of us all</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="7">
He was oppressed, and he was afllicted, yet he opened not his mouth; he is brought
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">as a lamb</P>
to the slaughter, and
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">as a sheep</P>
before her shearers is dumb, so he openeth not his mouth.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
In verse 8, while still talking about
<P ss="1" b="1">the Chosen One of God, Isaiah says very clearly that He would die</P>,
cut off out of the land of the living. This agrees perfectly with the prophecy of the seventy weeks in Daniel that also state that the Messiah would be killed (Daniel 9:26). If the texts declare that the Messiah was to die, why then expect Him to come and establish His Eternal Kingdom at His first coming? Why not accept that there are two kinds of prophecies regarding the Messiah.
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">One</P>
which talks about coming to die, to suffer, to be despised,
<P ss="1" b="1">to redeem the world.</P>
And <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">another</P> kind of prophecy which talks about
<P ss="1" b="1">coming to rule, to be respected, to punish, to bring order</P>.
Isn’t this true? And isn’t it Jesus who in His past First Coming and future Second Coming, is the only one who fulfills these prophecies? Why not therefore accept Jesus as the Messiah and Savior?
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 53:8">
<Verse>
He was taken from prison and from judgment; and who shall declare his generation? For
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">he was cut off out of the land of the living; for the transgression of my people was he stricken</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Dn 9:26">
<Verse verse="">
And after threescore and two weeks
<P ss="1" b="1">shall Messiah be cut off</P>, but not for himself; and the people of the prince that shall come shall destroy the city and the sanctuary; and the end thereof shall be with a flood, and unto the end of the war desolations are determined.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
Isn’t it quite clear from Isaiah 53:9 that
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">the Messiah will die?</P>
Whoever reads the Gospel will see that despite making His grave with the wicked (two thieves), a senator of Israel, Joseph of Arimathea, a rich man, asked Pilate for the body so that the part that reads “... with the rich in his death” might be fulfilled.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 53:9">
<Verse>
<P b="1">And he made his grave with the wicked, and with the rich in his death</P>; because he had done no violence, neither was any deceit in his mouth.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
Verse 10 clearly speaks about the resurrection of the God’s Chosen One, the Messiah, following His death. We see this in the text after “thou shalt make his soul an offering for sin”, where it says: “he shall see his seed, <P ss="1" b="1">he shall prolong his days.</P>” What other person with messianic stature can be alleged to have died for the world’s sins and then been resurrected except only Jesus Christ? Why not accept Him? The sacrifices of the lambs that the Israelite religion made were not a reflection of supposed “savagery” as many slanderers want us to see. These sacrifices were a symbol of the sacrifice that Jesus Christ was to make for our sins, the Lamb of God who takes away the sins of the world.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 53:10">
<Verse>
Yet it pleased the LORD to bruise him; he hath put him to grief; when thou shalt make his soul an offering for sin, he shall see his seed,
<P ss="1" b="1">he shall prolong his days</P>, and the pleasure of the LORD shall prosper in his hand.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
Finally, in verse 11 we see again how the text clarifies that it is speaking of the Messiah when God calls Him “my righteous servant”. There can be no doubt that the text refers to the Messiah in what it is about to say. Then it says that the
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">Messiah shall bear the sin of many</P> at the end of verse 12 where once again it states that the Messiah about whom it is speaking of will die. If the Messiah was to die, why say then that Jesus was not the Messiah because He died?
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 53:11-12">
<Verse verse="11">
He shall see of the travail of his soul, and shall be satisfied;
<P ss="1" b="1">by his knowledge shall</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">my righteous servant</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">justify many ; for</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">he shall bear their iniquities</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="12">
Therefore will I divide him a portion with the great, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong; because
<P ss="1" b="1">he hath poured out his soul unto death</P>
, and he was numbered with the transgressors; and
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">he bare the sin of many</P>
, and made intercession for the transgressors.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Let’s read now the entire portion of the Scriptures we have been studying by parts:</P>
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 52:13 to 53:12" wrap="true">
<Verse verse="(Isa 52:13)">
<P se="1" b="1">Behold, my servant</P> shall deal prudently, he shall be exalted and extolled, and be very high.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="14">
As many were astonied at thee; his visage was so marred more than any man, and his form more than the sons of men.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="15">
So shall <P ss="1" b="1">he sprinkle many nations</P>; the kings shall shut their mouths at him: for that which had not been told them shall they see; and that which they had not heard shall they consider.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="(Isa 53:1)">
<P se="1" b="1">Who hath believed our report?</P>
And to whom is the arm of the LORD revealed?
</Verse>

<Verse verse="2">
For he shall grow up before him as a tender plant, and as a root out of a dry ground, he hath no form nor comeliness; and when
<P ss="1" b="1">we shall see him, there is no beauty that we should desire him</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="3">
<P b="1">He is despised and rejected of men</P>; a man of sorrows, and acquainted with grief; and
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">we hid as it were our faces from him; he was despised</P>,
and
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">we esteemed him not</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="4">
<P b="1">Surely he hath borne our griefs, and carried our sorrows</P>; yet we did esteem him stricken, smitten of God, and afflicted.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="5">
<P b="1">But he was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities</P>; the chastisement of our peace was upon him; and with his stripes we are healed.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="6">
All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and
<P ss="1" b="1">the LORD hath laid on him the iniquity of us all</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="7">
He was oppressed, and he was afflicted, yet he opened not his mouth; he is brought <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">as a lamb</P> to the slaughter, and <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">as a sheep</P> before her shearers is dumb, so he openeth not his mouth.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="8">
He was taken from prison and from judgment, and who shall declare his generation?
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">For he was cut off out of the land of the living</P>
<P b="1">; for the transgression of my people was he stricken.</P>
</Verse>

<Verse verse="9">
<P b="1">And he made his grave with the wicked, and with the rich in his death</P>; because he had done no violence, neither was any deceit in his mouth.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="10">
Yet it pleased the LORD to bruise him; he hath put him to grief.
<P ss="1" b="1">When thou shalt make his soul an offering for sin</P>,
he shall see his seed,
<P ss="1" b="1">he shall prolong his days</P>,
and the pleasure of the LORD shall prosper in his hand.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="11">
He shall see of the travail of his soul, and shall be satisfied;
<P ss="1" b="1">by his knowledge shall my righteous servant justify many; for he shall bear their iniquities.</P>
</Verse>

<Verse verse="12">
Therefore will I divide him a portion with the great, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong; because
<P ss="1" b="1">he hath poured out his soul</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">unto death</P>;
and he was numbered with the transgressors; and
<P ss="1" b="1">he bare the sin of many</P>, and made intercession for the transgressors.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Alexander, Caesar, Napoleon and Christ</P>
<P ss="1" se="1" u="1">The Greeks are proud of Alexander the Great</P>
and <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">his bloody battles</P> to conquer the world.
<P ss="1" se="1" u="1">The Italians venerate Julius Caesar</P>
despite the <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">bloody battles</P> he carried out.
<P ss="1" u="1">The French boast of Napoleon Bonaparte</P>, because he conquered a short-lived empire while <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">bleeding</P> France and all of Europe.
<P ss="1" b="1">However the Jews are ashamed of the Jewish Jesus Christ</P>. They despise and reject Him. Some even hate Him. And they do all of that despite the fact that
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">it was with His own blood</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">and not the blood of someone else,</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">with His own suffering</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">and not the suffering of someone else that He redeems us from our sins and has conquered an enduring dominion of thousands of millions of</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">volunteer subiects</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Oh sons of Israel, are you right to be ashamed of Jesus Christ instead of being proud of Him? Is it right for you to despise, reject…and even hate Him? What bad thing has Jesus done to His people?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">If</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Rome</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">has falsified Christ’s teaching and has done harm to the Jews while hypocritically invoking His name</P>, is that why Jesus is considered worthy of contempt and hate?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
This is as unjust as if the Japanese hated the Jews because Albert Einstein, a Jew genius, provided the theory for the invention of the atomic bomb that the Americans used against Hiroshima and Nagasaki. Or it is as if the whole world because of fear for an impending nuclear holocaust, would decide to destroy the Jews or decide to hate Moses, David or Solomon, because Albert Einstein was the person who made the atomic bomb possible.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Jesus Christ never did anything against the Jews. Hating Jesus
<P ss="1" b="1">because the Roman Church used His name to persecute the Jews</P>, is absolutely unjust.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
The Hebrew Scriptures (the Old Testament), that the Jews accept, speaks a hundred times more severely against the Jews than the New Testament. Even though the Jews do not accept it, it contains only a few reproaches, <P ss="1" b="1">and is filled with words of good will towards the Jews</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Sons of Israel, reconsider the position against Jesus that many of you have, because it will be hard to defend and maintain this attitude when as with all of humanity, each one has to appear before the judgment throne of God in the presence of His Messiah.
</Paragraph>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 3">
<Paragraph>
In the Old Testament there are two kinds of prophecies about the coming of the Messiah.
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">One kind</P> is about the First Coming of Christ when He came as the Lamb of God to suffer for our sins as we have seen in Isaiah, chapters 52 and 53. This prophecy announces that the People of Israel will reject Him. Another prophecy about the First Coming is found in Isaiah 7:14 where it is proclaimed that He will be born of a virgin.
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">The other kind of prophecy</P> proclaims the Second Coming when He will come to rule and bring order and justice to the world.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">Roman Catholicism</P> has falsified the teachings of Christ and done damage to the Jews while hypocritically invoking His name. It is not logical, nor just for the Jews to be against Jesus because of this. It is precisely this Jew who has conquered and put under His feet millions of “goyim”, using His own blood and not everyone else’s blood the way Alexander the Great, Julius Caesar and Napoleon Bonaparte did. The peoples of these leaders are proud of these conquering leaders, but the Jewish people unjustly detest Jesus.
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
