<Chapter chapter="5" title="Other prophecies">
<Section title="The Messiah is to be born in Bethlehem. Jesus was born in Bethlehem.">

<Paragraph>
If someone does not want to accept the fact that the birth of Jesus in Bethlehem proves that He is the Messiah, he should accept that whoever does come claiming to be the Messiah has to prove that He was born in Bethlehem. The only person who until now has complied with this and <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">all of the other conditions of messiahship</P> has been Jesus. In addition, what other person with messianic stature has been born in Bethlehem?
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Micah 5:2">
<Verse>
But thou, <P ss="1" b="1">Bethlehem Ephratah</P>, though thou be little among the thousands of Judah, yet <P ss="1" b="1">out of thee shall he come forth unto me that is to be ruler in Israel</P>; whose goings forth have been from of old, from everlasting.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
There are many other proofs like this that some prefer to call small “coincidences,” that prove that Jesus Christ is the Messiah. Let’s examine some of these other proofs.
</Paragraph>
</Section>

<Section title="Psalm 22 prophesies about Jesus Christ">
<Paragraph>
All through a reading of Psalm 22, the many similarities with things that happened to Jesus are notable. Consequently, it is easy to deduce that this is a prophecy about Him.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1" u="1" se="1">The first similarity</P> is verse one; that is similar to the exclamation that Jesus made from the cross seen in Matthew 27:46.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 22:1">
<Verse>
<P b="1" se="1">My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?</P> Why art thou so far from helping me, and from the words of my roaring?
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Mt 27:46">
<Verse>
And about the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, saying: Eli, Eli, lama sabachthani? That is to say: <P ss="1" b="1">My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?</P>
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
When Jesus was on the cross, carrying on His person the sins of all of us, He was converted into the most sinful being in the universe. That is why God, who could not tolerate sin, abandoned Him. This is how by dying like the sacrificial lamb, He paid for the sins of all those that accept the redemption that He gives us. It is like in the ancient sacrifices, if you laid hands voluntarily in the lamb, if you accepted it, your sins were forgiven; if you didn’t accepted it didn’t avail you.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1" u="1">The second similarity</P> is in verse 8 where the ridicule of the priests, the scribes and the Pharisees towards Jesus is anticipated. They said that if it is true that God is pleased with Him, that God would save Him from the torment He was in. (Matthew 27:43).
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 22:8">
<Verse>
He trusted on the LORD that he would deliver him; let him <P ss="1" b="1">deliver him, seeing he delighted in him</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Mt 27:43">
<Verse>
He trusted in God; <P ss="1" b="1">let him deliver him now, if he will have him</P>; for he said: I am the Son of God.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">If God freed Jesus from the cross, then He would not have died for our sins</P>, and we would continue to be eternally condemned. This is why God did not save Him. That is why God sent him. This is something that his enemies did not understand nor did they want to understand.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1" u="1">The third similarity</P> is found in verse 16 of this Psalm where it says that <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">“they pierced” his hands and feet</P> which is what happened publicly to Jesus. In Spanish the translation of this Psalm by de León Dujovne y Manasés and Moisés Konstantynowski, printed by Editorial S. Sigal, Corrientes 2854, Buenos Aires, Argentina, does not use the words for pierced, but rather the word for “binding” <P ss="1" b="1">which is evidently not in the original</P>. To solve this, again you must find a Jewish “sabra” to translate and demonstrate who is correct. However without looking for help, it is only necessary to see that in that translation the phrase “binding me” is found in a parenthesis which indicates that the word does not exist in Hebrew, but rather was added by the translators. In the Hebrew version mentioned verse 16 has the number 17.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1" u="1">The fourth similarity</P> is found in verse 18 where it says that <P ss="1" b="1">they part my garments among them, and cast lots upon my vesture</P>. Matthew 27:35 and other Gospels narrate how this was fulfilled in Jesus.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 22:18">
<Verse>
They part my garments among them, and cast lots upon my vesture.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Mt 27:35">
<Verse>
<P b="1">And they crucified him, and parted his garments, casting lots</P>, that it might be fulfilled which was spoken by the prophet: <P ss="1" b="1">They parted my garments among them, and upon my vesture did they cast lots</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">
In summary the following verses of Psalm 22 are in agreement with what happened to Christ.
</P>
</Paragraph>

<Cite wrap="true">
<Verse>
-My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me? ( in verse 1)
</Verse>

<Verse>
-All they that see me laugh me to scorn, they shoot out the lip, they shake the head. He trusted on the LORD that he would deliver him. Let him deliver him, seeing he delighted in him. (in verses 7 & 8)
</Verse>

<Verse>
-For dogs have compassed me, the assembly of the wicked have inclosed me; they pierced my hands and my feet. (in verse 16)
</Verse>

<Verse>
-They part my garments among them, and cast lots upon my vesture. ( in verse 18)
</Verse>
</Cite>
</Section>

<Section title="The prophecy of David about the resurrection of Jesus Christ">
<Paragraph>
Let us examine one of David’s prophecies on the resurrection of Christ, the Messiah, the Holy One of God. Since David was a prophet and since his body decayed (was corrupted) in his sepulcher, a passage of Psalm 16 must be a prophecy about the Messiah because David could not be talking about himself.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
What is said here could not refer to David since his body has decayed and remained in his sepulcher. On the other hand the body of Jesus did not. If we read the history of Jesus, we see that he was resurrected on the third day; <P ss="1" b="1">He did not suffer corruption nor did He remain in the sepulcher</P>, since he ascended to Heaven. For this reason <P ss="1" b="1">this is a prophecy about the resurrection of Jesus</P>. About whom else does this prophecy coincide so perfectly?
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 16:10">
<Verse>
For thou wilt not leave my soul in hell; <P ss="1" b="1">neither wilt thou suffer</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">thine Holy One</P> <P ss="1" b="1">to see corruption</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>
</Section>

<Section title="Let’s see a prophecy about the Wise Men">
<Paragraph>
 Here there are two references that clearly point to Christ’s birth. Verse 2 of the 60th chapter of Isaiah says that “the glory of the LORD will be risen upon thee.” Who is God’s glory except for His Messiah? Later in the same verse 2 so as to assure us that this passage is not a metaphor is said: “but <P ss="1" b="1">the LORD shall arise upon thee</P>, and his glory shall be seen upon thee.”
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Lastly, remember that regarding the Wise Men who were gentile princes, the text says: “And the Gentiles shall come to thy light, and kings to the brightness of thy rising.” In fact the gentile kings did follow the star of Bethlehem, the light that guided them to Jesus. Who else other than Jesus has fulfilled these prophecies?
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 60:1-3">
<Verse verse="1">
Arise, shine; for thy light is come, and <P ss="1" b="1">the glory of the LORD is risen upon thee</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="2">
For, behold, the darkness shall cover the earth, and gross darkness the people; <P ss="1" b="1">but the LORD shall arise upon thee, and his glory shall be seen upon thee</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="3">
<P b="1">And the Gentiles shall come to thy light, and kings to the
brightness of thy rising</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>
</Section>

<Section title="The Messiah riding on a donkey">
<Paragraph>
 Another prophecy is that of the King that comes to Jerusalem riding on an ass instead of the traditional spirited white steed, as the mistaken tradition teaches. Verse 9 shows us that <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">the person riding the ass is the King of Zion</P> during his First Coming. Verse 10 also shows that it is speaking about the Messiah, because it says that <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">his dominion shall be from sea even to sea, and from the river even to the ends of the Earth</P> referring to the Second Coming. From this it is evident that the Messiah was to come to Jerusalem riding on an ass.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Zch 9:9-10">
<Verse verse="9">
Rejoice greatly, O daughter of Zion; shout, O daughter of Jerusalem, behold, <P ss="1" b="1">thy King cometh unto thee. He is just, and having salvation; lowly, and riding</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">upon an ass</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and upon a colt the foal of an ass</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="10">
And I will cut off the chariot from Ephraim, and the horse from Jerusalem, and the battle bow shall be cut off; <P ss="1" b="1">and</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">he shall speak peace unto the heathen</P>; <P ss="1" b="1">and</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">his dominion shall be from sea even to sea, and from the river even to the ends of the Earth</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
That the King of Zion was to come riding on a donkey during his First Coming was fulfilled by Jesus on the day of his triumphal entry into Jerusalem on Palm Sunday as is seen in Matthew 21:1-5. This should be enough to prove that Christ is the Messiah. But in case someone wants to allege that Christ did this precisely to prove that He was to be the Messiah, one can answer with the following: It is not logical that He would do this to pretend to be the Messiah because we all know of <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">the mistaken Jewish tradition</P> that <P ss="1" b="1">the Messiah was to come riding on a white horse</P>, not a donkey.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Although the Sacred Scriptures clearly state that it was a donkey, just the same, what counts is what the people and the religious leaders believed. If Christ would have wanted to make others believe He was the Messiah, He would have ridden in on a white horse. However, he came mounted on an ass because He was not seeking to fool people into accepting Him as a Messiah because He rode on a donkey, since they believed in their tradition instead of the Scriptures.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">I said that to believe the Messiah will come riding a white horse is a mistaken Jewish tradition</P>, because the Old Testament does not say so in any of its books. However, <P ss="1" b="1">Prophet Daniel told us that the Messiah will come on the clouds</P>, not in a white horse, when he was to receive dominion, glory, and everlasting kingdom over the whole world.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Dn 7: 13-14">
<Verse verse="13">
I saw in the night visions, and, <P ss="1" b="1">behold, one like the Son of man</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">came with the clouds of heaven</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and came to the Ancient of days, and they brought him near before him</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="14">
<P b="1" u="1">And there was given him dominion, and glory, and a kingdom, that all people, nations, and languages, should serve him; his dominion is an everlasting dominion, which shall not pass away, and his kingdom that which shall not be destroyed</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>
</Section>

<Section title="The one who pours the spirit of grace is the one who was pierced">
<Paragraph>
 Another prophecy that is in agreement with the person of Jesus Christ is the one that states that the one who pours the spirit of grace is the one who was pierced. There are many clues that have been given in the Old Testament so that the Messiah could be recognized when He came by all who wish to acknowledge Him. Among these clues is the following passage.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Zch 12:10">
<Verse>
<P b="1" u="1">And I will pour</P> <P ss="1" b="1">upon the house of David, and upon the inhabitants of Jerusalem, the spirit of grace</P> and of supplications. And <P ss="1" b="1">they shall look</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">upon me whom they have pierced</P>, and they shall mourn for him, as one mourneth for his only son, and shall be in bitterness for him, as one that is in bitterness for his firstborn.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
It is evident that <P ss="1" b="1">the same person who pours the “spirit of grace” over the inhabitants of Jerusalem is also the one “whom they have pierced”</P>. Wasn’t Jesus pierced on the cross? Could it be that the “forty” “coincidences” of this sort that appear in the Old Testament and that indicate that Jesus is the Messiah are “pure coincidences”? It does not matter if you do not care to acknowledge the existence of electricity despite the proofs of its existence; if you touch a live wire, the result will be the same, whether you believe in electricity or not.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">Jesus will come again</P> and this time He will establish His kingdom whether you believe it or not; and you will be lost if you have not wanted to entreat that He save you. He does not oblige you to be saved, He did all He could to freely give you the salvation. He was the Lamb of God that takes away the sins of the world, He is the one symbolized by the lambs that were sacrificed in the Temple. <P ss="1" b="1">He was the one symbolized by the lamb killed on the Passover day</P>. <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">That is whv he was crucified the same day of the Passover</P>. He gives you the gift of cleansing from sin, but He does not force you to accept this gift if you want to reject it. For a gift to be a gift there are two phases: someone gives and someone accepts the gift.
</Paragraph>
</Section>

<Section title="The Messiah was going to be born of a virgin">
<Paragraph>
 Look at the prophecy of Isaiah 7:14 where it states that the Messiah is to be born of a virgin, that is a woman who has never had relations with a man. This prophecy is a clear signal that Jesus Christ is the Messiah for anyone who wishes to examine it with sincerity; just like the prophecy of the seventy weeks.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 7:14">
<Verse>
Therefore <P ss="1" b="1">the Lord himself shall give you</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">a sign</P>: Behold, <P ss="1" b="1">a virgin shall conceive, and bear a son, and shall call his name Immanuel</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">There are some who reject this</P>, saying that the Hebrew word that is translated “virgin” could equally means “young woman”. If in fact the word used in the Hebrew has two possible meanings and can mean “virgin” or “young woman”, it is evident to anyone that the correct meaning to choose for the translation is “virgin”. Why?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Verse 14 say that <P ss="1" b="1">God will give us a sign</P>, that is to say, <P ss="1" b="1">something</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">unusual</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">something</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">miraculous</P>. Who would say that it would be a miraculous sign from God if a young woman had a son? Isn’t this normal? However, <P ss="1" b="1">it is indeed a great sign if a virgin has a son</P>. Therefore it is more than reasonable that, given the context, of the two alternative meanings that they say the word has, that “virgin” is the meaning must be chosen for translation.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
The most reasonable way to understand what verse 14 says is to accept that a virgin will bear a son, and that this child is Emmanuel (God with us). Nothing else is needed to realize that this son that is to be born of a virgin is the Messiah.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
There are those that refute the passage, saying that these verses (Isaiah 7:14-16) refer to the son of Isaiah, the son that is mentioned in the next chapter, in 8:3-4, and not to the Messiah. If the phrase “the virgin will conceive, and bear a son” refers to Isaiah’s wife and his son, then we must conclude that they are accepting for Isaiah, his wife and son the miracle of the virginal conception that they are denying for Joseph, Mary and Jesus.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 8:3-4">
<Verse verse="3">
And I went unto the prophetess; and she conceived, and bare a son. Then said the LORD to me: <P ss="1" b="1">Call his name</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Maher-shalal-hash-baz</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="4">
For before the child shall have knowledge to cry, My father, and my mother, the riches of Damascus and the spoil of
Samaria shall be taken away before the king of Assyria.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
In addition to this, one must note that although both passages seem to be talking about the same thing, in reality they are about two different things. In the first passage (chapter 7) the passage says that the child is to be named Emmanuel, but the second passage (in chapter 8) says that they are to name the child: Maher-shalal-hash-baz. <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">Both names signify two different things: the first signifies: “God with us”</P> which is in agreement with what Jesus Christ proclaimed about himself, that He is the Son of God. <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">The second name means: “speed to the spoils of war, hasten the booty.”</P> The first passage says: “before the child shall know to refuse the evil and choose the good.” In chapter 8 we find: “before the child shall have knowledge to cry, My father, and my mother.” Additionally, <P ss="1" b="1">the spirit of the first passage is peace; the spirit of the second is punishment</P>. It is obvious that they are not about the same matter, but rather two different things with some similarities between them.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
It is interesting to observe that despite the fact that neither Judaism nor Islamism will admit that this prophecy refers to the Messiah, one of the greatest religions of the world, Christianity, is based on this passage.
</Paragraph>
</Section>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 5">
<Paragraph>
There are various prophecies in the Old Testament that indicate that Jesus is the Messiah. One of these is Micah 5:2 that says that the Messiah will be born in Bethlehem. Another is psalm 22 which describes the events that occurred when Christ was on the cross. We also have psalm 16:10 where David announces that the body of the Messiah will not see corruption. Another prophecy is Isaiah 60:1-3 which is about the birth of the Messiah and the visitation of the wise men. Another is the prophecy about the Messiah coming to Jerusalem mounted on an ass found Zachariah 9:9-10. In the same vein we can observe things like Zachariah 12:10 that says that the Messiah was to be pierced which is precisely what happened to Jesus on the cross. As we have seen, there are various prophecies that point to Jesus as the Messiah.
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
