<Chapter chapter="9" title="Is Jesus Christ the Son of God?">
<Paragraph>
 The entire Psalm 2 convinces us, <P ss="1" b="1">without a doubt that it describes the Messiah</P>. Among other things, because verses 8 and 9 show that his Kingdom extends to all people and not just Zion. This Psalm shows that God has a Son (verses 7 and 12); that the Son is the Messiah, the one who would reign over Zion (verses 6-9); and that one must serve God as much as his Son (verses 11 and 12). Let’s see.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 2:1-12">
<Verse verse="1">
Why do the heathen rage, and the people imagine a vain thing?
</Verse>
<Verse verse="2">
The kings of the Earth set themselves, and the rulers take counsel together, <P ss="1" b="1">against the LORD, and</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">against his anointed</P>, saying:
</Verse>
<Verse verse="3">
Let us break their bands asunder, and cast away their cords from us.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="4">
 He that sitteth in the Heavens shall laugh, the Lord shall have them in derision.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="5">
Then shall he speak unto them in his wrath, and vex them in his sore displeasure.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="6">
Yet have I set my king upon my holy hill of Zion.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="7">
I will declare the decree, the LORD hath said unto me: <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Thou art my Son</P>; <P ss="1" b="1">this day have I begotten thee</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="8">
<P b="1">Ask of me, and I shall give thee the heathen for thine inheritance, and the uttermost parts of the Earth for thy possession</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="9">
<P b="1">Thou shalt break them with a rod of iron; thou shalt dash them in pieces like a potter’s vessel</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="10">
Be wise now therefore, O ye kings, be instructed, ye judges of the Earth.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="11">
Serve the LORD with fear, and rejoice with trembling.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="12">
<P b="1">Kiss the Son, lest he be angry</P>, and ye perish from the way, when his wrath is kindled but a little. Blessed are all they that put their trust in him.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
As we have read, since the remote time of antiquity, before the New Testament, it was known that a Son of God existed, truth denied by Muslims. In verse 2 of the passage recently read we see that it is speaking about the Messiah and in verse 7, God says to that Messiah, “Thou art my Son”. In 8 and 9, he promises that he will give Him power over the whole Earth, ending in verse 12 by saying to kiss the Son. It is evident that from the most remote part of antiquity of the Old Testament, it is known that God has a Son, a special being that has all the characteristics of an Only Begotten Son.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Something similar can be found when referring to God in Proverbs 30:4 says, “<P i="1" b="1">...What is his name, and what is his son’s name</P>, <P ss="1" i="1">if thou canst tell?</P>” This part of Proverbs 30:4 is in concordance with Psalm 2:7 which says, “<P i="1">the LORD hath said unto me</P>: <P ss="1" i="1" b="1" u="1">Thou art my Son</P>”.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
It is declared here that the Creator has a Son, a particular and special son; not just one of his creatures whom he called son. It is also good to note that the first verse of this chapter of Proverbs, states that this is a prophecy, something inspired by God.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">I have never been contented reading the entire Bible many times</P>, but in addition, in the many times I have read it, I have tried to read it in as many different translations as possible. In that way, I have read <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">the Reina-Valera</P> the old version (which is the best); I have read the <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">Scio de San Miguel</P> (which is the best among the Catholic Bibles); I have read <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Nácar-Colunga</P>; the photographic copy of the translation of <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">Casiodoro de Reina</P> only, before the revision by Cipriano Valera, which was printed in 1573; the translation by <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Torres Amat</P>; <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the photographic copy of the original Cipriano de Valera version</P>, printed in 1602; I have read the <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Reina-Valera printed in 1855</P>; the <P ss="1" b="1">Russellists version</P>; <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the New American Standard</P>, in English; <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the King James Version</P>, also in English which is the best English one; the <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">New King James Version</P>; <P ss="1" b="1">the modern version</P>; <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the Hebrew Old Testament</P> translated to Spanish by Rabbis; the <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Reina-Valera 1960</P> version; <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the Chronological Bible</P>; and I can’t remember how many other versions, not counting how many times I have repeated the reading of the before mentioned versions. And when I say that I have read these versions, I am saying from Genesis to Revelations, as I always do, without skipping over anything. This is not counting the “sacred” books of the Seventh Day Adventists, the Mormons, Armstrong’s World Wide Church, the Russellites, the Koran, etc.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
What I am trying to say by mentioning all of this, is that I am not a narrow minded person. I am not one of those that see everything only through the crack his sect permits him the scrutiny of truth. I do not belong to any sect, nor am I a person that only knows what he read in the translation of the Bible which is authorized by his sect, because I have read all the translations of the Bible of all of them.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">Because I have precisely done that, it is that I have</P> knowledge and moral strength to recommend the Old Version of the Reina-Valera as the best one that exists. <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">Because I have read all these versions it is that I can say that there are errors in them; a few in some and many in others; and that</P> there are even voluntary alterations. <P ss="1" b="1">This is the case of the Hebrew version in Spanish by Leon Dujovne, Manasés y Moisés Konstantynowski, printed by Editorial S. Sigal, Corrientes 2854, Buenos Aires, Argentina</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
As in all dishonest sectarians, the Hebrew version translated into Spanish maintains the purity of the Bible in everything that is not a frank contradiction of its dogmas. When it comes to those passages that clearly and unequivocally signal out Jesus Christ as the Messiah, they distort it, omit it or “explain” it.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">This is the case with Psalm 2:12. In Verse 11 of the Reina-Valera version, speaking about God, it says: “Serve the LORD with fear, and rejoice with trembling. Kiss the Son (it says in the beginning of 12) lest he be angry....” As we can see, this is a clear and open reference to the Son of God</P>; this absolutely supports and is totally within the concept that God has a son. This is a concept that the Jews and the Muslims totally deny.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In order to not “give in”, in the Jewish translation to the Spanish previously mentioned, they omit the phrase “Kiss the Son”, and they substitute it for the false phrase “Get armed with purity”. This falsification of the Sacred Scriptures they do knowingly, it is not an error. They are impostors who deceive those who trust in them as translators and they will have to account for this dirty trick in the Day of Judgment.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Now, it would be fitting to ask me</P>: “<P b="1">You, who do not know Hebrew</P>, how can you know which translators are right? How dare you ‘judge’ your fellow man?”
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
When I reach a conclusion against something sustained by “A”, I do not do so based on what “B”, which is an antagonist of “A” tells me, but in what “A” tells me. God is great and powerful and is not without testimony <P ss="1" b="1">of the truth, even in the Bibles that are altered and rigged. Even the Bible translated by the Russellites, which is altered from Genesis to Revelations, testifies against themselves, against their own doctrines!</P>
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
As in the case of Jewish translation, I did not know Hebrew, I had to rig a solution. I had an edition of the Old Testament in Hebrew (the version printed in Israel by the editor “Sinai Publishing” <P ss="1" b="1">in Tel Aviv</P>), <P ss="1" b="1">so I took a photocopy of that psalm from the book. I took that copy to a Hebrew friend</P>, a scientist specialized in biophysics, a sabra Jew, born and raised in Israel who worked with me, and I asked him to translate the words of verse 12. My Hebrew friend, who spoke and read the Hebrew language as his native language, and English as an acquired language, answered me in latter one, that it was the common language which we used to communicate: “<P b="1">Here says: Kiss the son</P>”.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
What these translators had modified in order to translate to Spanish, the other Rabbis had not dared to modify in the Hebrew. Why? The high cleric of all the sects, the directors of erroneous sects are not willing to tell the truth to the sheep from which they shear the wool. On another hand, the believer in general is lazy to read the Bible, the Christian as well as the Jew. He will read it even less in a language he does not know. That is why in translating it to the common language of the country in which they live, they modify it, but in an unknown language, in the language only known by the Rabbis and high clergy of the mentioned country, in the language read by only those who have sectarian and economic interests in their religion, it is not necessary to modify it. Even if they read the truth and perceive it, they will not believe it because they do not want to do so.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
When Jesus once again demonstrated his divinity in resurrecting Lazarus, the sincere Jews accepted it as proof that Jesus was the Messiah. Nevertheless, the insincere, prejudicial and those belonging to the Pharisee and Sadducee clergy, determined that it was necessary to kill Lazarus, so that there would be no proof of his resurrection (John 12:9-10). All of this will have to be accounted for in the Day of Judgment.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">On the other hand, the multitude of sincere Jewish believers, that are sincerely mistaken, who were born in Israel and know the Hebrew language, are not willing to allow the Sacred Scripture to be modified in a language that they understand: the Hebrew language; and of which they have hundreds of orthodox copies</P>. Sincere Rabbis, in all countries, will not allow either Scripture to be modified. That is why the translators can only make partial alterations and only in a language in which any falsification will not produce much antagonism or problems among their own people.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Also in the book of the prophet Ezekiel</P>, as I have pointed out in other places, the fact that God has a son is evidenced; not just any creature, but a special being which He considers His son. In the Hebrew Bible which is translated to Spanish, even though the translation has not been altered, the number of verses differ, what we have here in Ezekiel 21:10, they have in Ezekiel 21:15. This difference in the numeration occurs frequently in this translation.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ezk 21:8-12">
<Verse verse="8">
Again the word of the LORD came unto me, saying:
</Verse>

<Verse verse="9">
Son of man, prophesy, and say: Thus saith the LORD, Say: A sword, a sword is sharpened, and also furbished.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="10">
It is sharpened to make a sore slaughter; it is furbished that it may glitter. Should we then make mirth? <P ss="1" b="1">It contemneth the rod of</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">my son</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">as every tree</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="11">
And he hath given it to be furbished, that it may be handled, this sword is sharpened, and it is furbished, to give it into the hand of the slayer.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="12">
Cry and howl, son of man, <P ss="1" b="1">for it shall be upon</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">my people</P>, it shall be upon all the princes of Israel; terrors by reason of the sword shall be upon <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">my people</P>; smite therefore upon thy thigh.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
It is good to remember upon reading verse 10, what is later said in verse 12. There, we can learn that the sword which is mentioned <P ss="1" b="1">would be sent against the nation of Israel and against its princes</P>. We also see there that it specifies that the fear of the sword referred to “my nation”. That indicates to us that the word “son” which exist in the phrase “<P i="1">It contemneth the rod of</P> <P ss="1" u="1" i="1">my son</P>, <P ss="1" i="1">as every tree</P>.”, cannot possibly be referring to the nation of Israel as some want us to see. It cannot be referring to the nation of Israel, because what it is saying about the “son”, is a complaint because they undervalue the son, while what they are saying about Israel is that it will be punished by sword. It is to say, that on one hand, <P ss="1" b="1">God complains that his son is undervalued</P>, while on the other hand, <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">God says that he will punish Israel</P> by way of sword. It is not logical to think that God will punish Israel because that nation (Israel) was undervalued. The logical thing is to think that Christ, His Son, is the one who is undervalued, and that is what God is complaining about, while Israel is punished by sword, and that is what God is announcing in this passage (8-32).
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Some would be willing to believe that Jesus Christ is the Messiah</P>, but it is hard for them to accept that he is a divine being. The great King David considered that the Messiah was his Lord. Being the Messiah a descendant of David from a carnal point of view, it is not logical for him to call him Lord. However, David refers to God as well as the Messiah as Lord.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In the case of David saying the phrase “God said to my Lord”, it is clear that he refers to God the Father as God, and that the person which calls “my Lord”, (that is the Lord of David) is the one who sits at the right hand of God. By logic, <P ss="1" b="1">the one who sits at the right hand of God can only be the Messiah, and to be worthy to sit at the right hand of God, have to be a being of His same “class”</P>. The fact that David calls the Messiah, “Lord” clearly indicates that the Messiah was not going to be a human being, but someone in a superior hierarchy, someone divine.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 110:1">
<Verse>
A Psalm of David. <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">The LORD</P> <P ss="1" b="1">said unto</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">my Lord</P>: <P ss="1">Sit thou at my right hand</P>, until I make thine enemies thy footstool.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
If the Messiah announced here was a human being, the great King David would not have called him “my Lord” for two reasons. <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">The first</P>, because the founder of the dynasty was David and the Messiah would be a mere descendant of the founder, therefore the founder was superior for being the founder and for being an ancestor. <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">The second</P>, because never ever, and even less during that time, would someone refer to a descendant as “my Lord”. It was the descendants that treated their ancestors with such respect. Therefore, if David treats the Messiah as “my Lord”, it is evident that he was not going to be a human being, but a divine one. Otherwise David did not have to call him “<P b="1">my Lord</P>” in any event.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">In a nutshell</P>, David, who is a greatly considered man in Judaism, <P ss="1" b="1">and who was a prophet</P>, upon calling the Messiah his Lord, proves that he did not consider Him to be human. If he would have considered Him human, he did not have to call him his Lord, because he was going to be one of his descendants. This veneration manifested by David towards the Messiah indicates that he was someone more than a human chosen by God to be the King of Israel, coming from David’s offspring.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
This thought on the divinity of Jesus Christ is in concordance to what is stated in Psalm 45:6-7. Upon saying in verse 6 “<P i="1">Thy throne, O God..</P>” it is clear that this refers to a divine being. In continuing, in verse 7, speaking to that person and saying, “<P i="1">therefore God, thy God, hath anointed thee</P>”, is showing us that whom he was speaking to first, was not God the Father, but someone who had been anointed by God. It pertained to one who had God in a superior place from his, or therefore, the Messiah. Upon seeing that previously he treated the Messiah as a divine being helps us see that the true Messiah is a divine being, even though he is not
God the Father.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 45:6-7">
<Verse verse="6">
<P b="1">Thy throne, O God</P>, is for ever and ever; the sceptre of thy kingdom is a right sceptre.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="7">
Thou lovest righteousness, and hatest wickedness, therefore <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">God, thy God, hath anointed thee</P> with the oil of gladness above thy fellows.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
The Hebrew translation to Spanish by Dujovne & Konstantynowski, instead of including this passage in the previously mentioned verses, it is found in 7 and 8. In addition, the first verse is twisted by being translated in the following manner: “your throne shall be established by God…”, which takes away the connotation of the divinity of the Messiah. However, the best way to know who is correct is to take a Bible in Hebrew, photocopy that passage, cut out those two verses (7 and 8) and give them to a Jew, born in Israel, without religious inclination so that he reads it without knowledge of what it is about and therefore be honest in its translation.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Also, there is the fact that in Isaiah 7:14, which we have already read, the son that the virgin was to give birth would be called Emmanuel, which is saying that the being it is speaking about would be divine. The word “Emmanuel” means “God is with us”.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
If after studying prophecies, we got to the conclusion that Christ is the Messiah, and he says that he is the Son of God and that he is a divine being, it is logical that we believe him, the Messiah doesn’t say lies.
</Paragraph>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 9">
<Paragraph>
Another thing that causes difficulty to those who read rabbinical writings, but not the Old Testament, is the affirmation that Christ is the son of God. However, we clearly saw in Psalm 2 that speaks about the Messiah and in this context it is said that God has a son, especially in verse 12. The same can be said for Proverbs 30:4, where it speaks about the Son of God and in Ezekiel 21:8-12. We also see that David, in Psalm 110:1 calls the Messiah by the name Lord. This is a sign that he was a being superior to man, because if not, the great King David would have not called him “my Lord”. He would have not treated him as a superior for two reasons: <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">first</P>, because the founder of the dynasty was David and the Messiah would merely be a descendant of the founder; and <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">secondly</P>, because never ever, but much less in that time, was a descendant be referred to or called “my Lord”. This thought about the divinity of the Messiah, is in concordance with what is said in Psalm 45:6-7, where the context tells us that it is talking about the Messiah. Upon verse 6 saying “<P i="1">Thy Throne, oh God…</P>” we see that he is speaking to a divine being. All of these verses, taken from the Old Testament, speak to us about the divinity of the Messiah, as the Son of God.
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
