<Chapter chapter="7" title="The destruction of the genealogies and the Messiah">

<Paragraph>
It has been clearly established that the Messiah had to be from the Tribe of Judah and specifically a descendent of David, as compiled from various passages of the prophets.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Jer 23:5-6 ">
<Verse verse="5">
Behold, the days come, saith the LORD, that <P ss="1" b="1">I will raise unto David a</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">righteous Branch, and a King shall reign</P> and prosper, and shall execute judgment and justice in the Earth.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="6">
<P b="1">In his days Judah shall be saved, and Israel shall dwell safely</P>. And this is his name whereby he shall be called: “The Lord our righteousness”.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Jer 33:15-17">
<Verse verse="15">
In those days, and at that time, <P ss="1" b="1">will I cause the</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Branch of righteousness</P> <P ss="1" b="1">to grow up unto David; and he shall execute judgment and righteousness in the land</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="16">
In those days shall Judah be saved, and Jerusalem shall dwell safely; and this is the name wherewith she shall be called, <P ss="1" b="1">The LORD our righteousness</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="17">
For thus saith the LORD; <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">David shall never want</P> a man to sit upon the throne of the house of Israel.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
These prophecies were given in Jeremiah’s epoch. After him, the kings of Israel or Judah no longer existed. For this reason, his prophecy does not refer to any of the kings that reigned in Israel or Judah.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Various prophecies show that one of the conditions that the Messiah had to fulfill was that he must be a descendent of David. The passage below shows this, given that the description can only refer to the Messiah and that beyond this relates him to David’s throne. Logically the Messiah has to be a proven descendent of David.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Isa 9:6-7">
<Verse verse="6">
For unto us a child is born, unto us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder; and his name shall be called Wonderful, Counsellor, The mighty God, The everlasting Father, The Prince of Peace.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="7">
<P b="1">Of the increase of his government and peace there shall be no end</P>, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">upon the throne of David</P>, and upon his kingdom, to order it, and to establish it with judgment and with justice from henceforth even for ever. The zeal of the LORD of hosts will perform this.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">When the people of Israel left Egypt</P>, many people left with them who were not Hebrews but that had joined with them in leaving. I suppose that they left in order to escape slavery. Exodus 12:38 shows this clearly.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ex 12:38">
<Verse>
<P b="1">And</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">a mixed multitude</P> <P ss="1" b="1">went up also with them</P>; and flocks, and herds, even very much cattle.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
Given that these people who joined in the exodus were not Hebrews, therefore their descendants while Israelites from a political point of view, were not Hebrews from a messianic point of view. That is they were not children of Abraham, Isaac or Jacob. The Messiah could not descend from them.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Other kind of people that mixed with the Hebrew, and that cannot be detected today unless the genealogies exist, are those bought as slaves, which were circumcised, and the not native sojourners who also were circumcised if they wanted to participate of the Passover, as stated in Ex 12:44 and 48.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ex 12:44">
<Verse>
But <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">every man's servant</P> that is bought for money, <P ss="1" b="1">when thou hast</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">circumcised him</P>, then shall he eat thereof.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Ex 12:48">
<Verse>
And <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">when a stranger</P> shall sojourn with thee, and will keep the Passover to the LORD, <P ss="1" b="1">let all his males be circumcised</P>, and then let him come near and keep it; <P ss="1" b="1">and he shall be as one that is born in the land</P>; for no uncircumcised person shall eat thereof.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
Upon mixing those people with the Hebrews, only by means of the genealogies could they be detected, to preclude them from being Levites, priests or messiah, given that they were not children of Abraham, Isaac, Jacob and David.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Also the descendants of Moses’ Father-in-law (Kenite) who were not Hebrews, became Israelites just like the multitude of the other foreigners that left Egypt during the exodus as the passage below states.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Similarly we read in Deuteronomy 23:7-8 that the descendants of the Egyptians and of the Edomites could form part of the “congregation of the LORD” in the third generation. In other words they were politically Israelites but they were neither Hebrews nor children of Abraham, Isaac, Jacob and David. The Messiah could not come from their descendants. <P ss="1" b="1">This is why the Israelites maintained meticulous registries of their genealogies</P>. They did this with the purpose of assuring that the Messiah descended from Abraham, Isaac, Jacob and David. They also wanted to be sure that their priests were descendants of Aaron.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Jdg 1:16">
<Verse>
And <P ss="1" b="1">the children of the Kenite</P>, Moses' father in law, went up out of the city of palm trees with the children of Judah into the wilderness of Judah, which lieth in the south of Arad; and <P ss="1" b="1">they went and dwelt among the people</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Dt 23:7-8">
<Verse verse="7">
Thou shalt not abhor <P ss="1" b="1">an Edomite</P>; for he is thy brother; thou shalt not abhor <P ss="1" b="1">an Egyptian</P>; because thou wast a stranger in his land.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="8">
<P b="1">The children that are begotten of them shall</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">enter into the congregation</P> <P ss="1" b="1">of the LORD in their third generation</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
These outsiders mixed with the people, but the Hebrews, who always zealously kept their genealogies, always knew which ones were descendants of Abraham, Isaac, Jacob, Aaron, David, etc., and who were descendants of the people who had joined with the Hebrews. <P ss="1" b="1">The Messiah had to descend from Abraham as well as from David, and Levites and priests had to be descendants of Levy and Aaron respectively</P>. One clear case of an Egyptian who had an Israelite descendant is found in Lev 24:10 and First Chronicles 2:35. If you continue to read this passage, you will see how many people were descendants of this Egyptian and registered in these genealogies. This kind of mixture was why the Israelites maintained their genealogy books with such perfection. No one that was not a descendant of Abraham and David could declare to be the Messiah, nor could anyone who was not a descendant of Aaron become a priest in the Temple.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Lev 24:10">
<Verse>
And the son of an Israelitish woman, <P ss="1" b="1">whose father was an Egyptian</P>, went out among the children of Israel; and this son of the Israelitish woman and a man of Israel strove together in the camp.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="I Chr 2:34-35">
<Verse verse="34">
Now Sheshan had no sons, but daughters. And Sheshan had <P ss="1" b="1">a servant</P>, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">an Egyptian</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">whose name was Jarha</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="35">
<P se="1" b="1">And Sheshan gave his daughter to Jarha</P> his servant to wife; and she bare him Attai.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
When the people of the North, the nation of Israel, was destroyed and its people were taken into captivity, they mixed among the inhabitants of Assyria and the surrounding areas and became lost among the people of the world. Even that the nation of the south, Judah, was composed of people from all the tribes of Israel, the majority were descendants of the tribe of Judah. Notwithstanding, since in the Temple and in Judah, genealogical records were being kept it was known who were Israelites by naturalization and who were Hebrews, descendants of Abraham and David. From among these, they knew who were from the tribe of Judah and among the latter, who were descendants of David. The descendants of David were the only ones who could give way to the Messiah. The descendants of Aaron were the only ones with the right to the priesthood. They also knew who were just Levites, without any rights to the priesthood.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In order to confirm that the components of the diverse Tribes of Israel were mixed in with the inhabitants of the Tribe of Judah, it is enough to read the passages I present below. To this, we could add the fact that from the beginning, the possession of the Tribe of Simeon was found in the territory of the Tribe of Judah, whose components united with the Tribe of Judah.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Not all of who in actuality call themselves Jews are descendants of the Tribe of Judah</P>. After the transmigration, the Israelites did not continue to live as each tribe in their region, but they mixed among themselves. In Jerusalem, there lived people from the tribes of Simeon, Benjamin, Ephraim, Manasseh and Judah as well as the Nethinims and the Levites. That same mixture of tribes is seen in Nehemiah 11:4. During that time, they knew what tribe they belonged to, because the genealogical books were still preserved. <P ss="1" b="1">After the destruction of Jerusalem and the Temple by the Romans, all was lost. Today</P>, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">no Jew knows what tribe he descends from</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Nowadays, we would never know if one who proclaimed himself to be the Messiah was or not from the Tribe of Judah and above all, a descendant of David, as it is supposed to be according to prophecy.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="I Chr 9:2-3">
<Verse verse="2">
Now the first inhabitants that dwelt in their possessions in their cities were, the <P ss="1" b="1">Israelites, the priests, Levites, and the Nethinims</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="3">
And in Jerusalem dwelt of the <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">children of Judah</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and of</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the children of Benjamin</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and of</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the children of Ephraim</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Manasseh</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="II Chr 15:9">
<Verse>
And he gathered <P ss="1" b="1">all</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Judah</P> <P ss="1" b="1">and</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Benjamin</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the strangers</P> <P ss="1" b="1">with them out of</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Ephraim</P> <P ss="1" b="1">and</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Manasseh</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and out of</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Simeon</P>; for they fell to him out of Israel in abundance, when they saw that the LORD his God was with him.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Section title="There are no existing genealogies today">
<Paragraph>
 Any Israelite, who is called a Jew, could be a descendant of an Egyptian, an Edomite, a Kenite or any other foreigner, the same as a descendant of Jacob or Aaron. No one can be certain of their ascendancy. Therefore, <P ss="1" b="1">today one could not guarantee if one who says is the Messiah is a son of David or descendant of an Egyptian. In addition, we could also not know whether he is a descendant of Aaron with a right to the priesthood or if he is a descendant of an Edomite or simply a Levite.</P>
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
This should be sufficient proof for any sincere Jew, who does not want to shut his eyes to the truth, to realize that <P ss="1" b="1">Jewish religion ended with the total destruction of the Temple and the loss of the genealogical records</P>. This occurred after the coming, crucifixion, death and resurrection of Jesus Christ. This should be a sufficient sign for them to understand that if there can never be a Jewish religion, nor priesthood, nor Temple, no another Messiah, Jesus had to be the Messiah. The prophecies of God regarding the coming of the Messiah cannot fail, so therefore there is no other possibility.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
That should cause Jews to reason, that if the genealogical tree of any Israelite cannot be known, and if God permitted such a thing to happen, it is because the Messiah has already come, and therefore, it is not necessary to know the ascendance of any other supposed “messiah”.
</Paragraph>
</Section>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 7">
<Paragraph>
The Jews kept very meticulous records of their genealogy. One of the reasons was that the Messiah had to be a descendant of Abraham and David. Another reason was to know who could be a priest by being a descendant of Aaron. Without the genealogies, no one could guarantee that they were descendants of those patriarchs. Given that when the Israelites left Egypt, many who were not descendants of Abraham joined them, and that during the time of the Judges and Kings there was also a great mix, the genealogies were indispensable.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Now a days not all that are called Jews are descendant of the tribe of Judah. In Jerusalem lived people from the tribes of Simeon, Benjamin, Ephraim, Manasseh, and Judah, beside Nethinims and Levites.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
During that time, they knew what tribe they were from, because the genealogical books were still kept. After the destruction of Jerusalem and the Temple by the Romans, all was lost, and <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">nowadays no Jew knows what tribe they descend from</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Therefore, no one can prove that he is the Messiah, son of Abraham and David. This demonstrates that Jesus Christ is the Messiah because now another one cannot be a messiah.
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
