<Chapter chapter="8" title="Genealogy and the priesthood">
<Paragraph>
 In God’s law, a very rigorous mandate was that only the sons of Aaron could be priests in the Temple. No one that was not from the lineage of Aaron could officiate as a priest, or he would have a death sentence. We shall see in addition in the book of Ezra how on one occasion, not having genealogical proof of Aaronic lineage in certain priests they were cast from the priesthood. Without authentic genealogical proof, neither priests nor Levites could officiate. <P ss="1" b="1">Even in the case in which through tradition their correct lineage was known, genealogical proof was required</P>. Let us see the requirements of the law of God, given by Moses for the priesthood. Notice specifically that it was absolutely prohibited for someone to exercise the priesthood if he wasn’t from the lineage of Aaron.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Numbers 1:51">
<Verse>
And when the tabernacle setteth forward, <P ss="1" b="1">the Levites shall take it down</P>, and when the tabernacle is to be pitched, <P ss="1" b="1">the Levites shall set it up</P>; <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">and the stranger that cometh nigh shall be put to death</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Numbers 3:4">
<Verse>
And <P ss="1" b="1">Nadab and Abihu died before the LORD</P>, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">when they offered strange fire</P> <P ss="1" b="1">before the LORD</P>, in the wilderness of Sinai, and they had no children; and Eleazar and Ithamar ministered in the priest's ojfice in the sight of Aaron their father.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Numbers 3:10">
<Verse>
And thou shalt appoint Aaron and his sons, and they shall wait on their priest’s ojfice; <P ss="1" b="1">and the stranger that cometh nigh shall be put to death</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Numbers 3:38">
<Verse>
But those that encamp before the tabernacle toward the east, even before the tabernacle of the congregation eastward, shall be Moses, and Aaron and his sons, keeping the charge of the sanctuary for the charge of the children of Israel; <P ss="1" b="1">and the stranger that cometh nigh shall be put to death</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Numbers 16:35-40">
<Verse verse="35">
And <P ss="1" b="1">there came out a fire from the LORD, and consumed the two hundred and fifty men that offered incense</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="36">
And the LORD spake unto Moses, saying,
</Verse>
<Verse verse="37">
Speak unto Eleazar the son of Aaron the priest, that he take up the censers out of the burning, and scatter thou the fire yonder; for they are hallowed.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="38">
The censers of these sinners against their own souls, let them make them broad plates for a covering of the altar, for they ojfered them before the LORD, therefore they are hallowed; and they shall be a sign unto the children of Israel.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="39">
And Eleazar the priest took the brasen censers, wherewith they
that were burnt had offered, and they were made broad plates for a covering of the altar,
</Verse>
<Verse verse="40">
<P b="1">to be a memorial unto the children of Israel, that</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">no stranger, which is not of the seed of Aaron</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">come near to offer incense before the LORD</P>; that he be not as Korah, and as his company, as the LORD said to him by the hand of Moses.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Number 18:1-7">
<Verse verse="1">
And the LORD said unto Aaron: <P ss="1" b="1">Thou and thy sons and thy father's house with thee shall bear the iniquity of the sanctuary, and thou and thy sons with thee shall bear the iniquity of your priesthood</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="2">
And thy brethren also of the tribe of Levi, the tribe of thy father, bring thou with thee, that they may be joined unto thee, and minister unto thee, but thou and thy sons with thee shall minister before the tabernacle of witness.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="3">
And they shall keep thy charge, and the charge of all the tabernacle. <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">Only they shall not come nigh the vessels of the sanctuary and the altar, that neither they, nor ye also, die</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="4">
And they shall be joined unto thee, and keep the charge of the tabernacle of the congregation, for all the service of the tabernacle, and <P ss="1" b="1">a stranger shall not come nigh unto you</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="5">
And ye shall keep the charge of the sanctuary, and the charge of the altar, <P ss="1" b="1">that there be no wrath any more upon the children of Israel</P>.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="6">
And I, behold, I have taken your brethren the Levites from among the children of Israel; to you they are given as a gift for the LORD, to do the service of the tabernacle of the congregation.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="7">
Therefore thou and thy sons with thee shall keep your priest's office for everything of the altar, and within the vail; and ye shall serve. I have given your priest's office unto you as a service of gift, and <P ss="1" b="1">the stranger that cometh nigh shall be put to death</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
You may have noticed that with God’s commandment, you didn’t play the game of am I or am I not a descendant of Aaron. Whoever dared to usurp this ministry was punished by capital punishment. That is the reason why we see in the book of Ezra that on one occasion, due to the fact that there was no genealogical proof, various individuals were cast out from the priesthood.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
From the reading of this passage which I present below, we realize <P ss="1" b="1">how strict was the issue of being</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">proven</P> <P ss="1" b="1">descendants of Aaron in order to exercise the priesthood</P>. Here we see that no one was permitted to be a priest if he could not <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">prove</P> <P ss="1" b="1" se="1">without a doubt</P> his Aaronic genealogy. The simple testimony of acquaintances or the name they may have had was not permitted as “proof”.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
The persons mentioned in verse 60 as well as the priests mentioned in verse 61 had genealogical problems. The priests in verse 61, however, had more problems, because by not being able to find the <P ss="1" b="1" se="1">genealogies that would prove</P> they were descendants of Aaron, they were <P ss="1" b="1">cast out of the priesthood</P>, as is seen in verse 62.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ezra 2:59-62">
<Verse verse="59">
And these were they which went up from Telmelah, Telharsa, Cherub, Addan, and Immer, <P ss="1" b="1">but they could not shew their father ‘s house, and their seed, whether they were of Israel</P>:
</Verse>
<Verse verse="60">
the children of Delaiah, the children of Tobiah, the children of Nekoda, six hundred fifty and two.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="61">
<P b="1">And of the children of the priests</P>: the children of Habaiah, the children of Koz, the children of Barzillai; which took a wife of the daughters of Barzillai the Gileadite, and was called after their name.
</Verse>
<Verse verse="62">
<P b="1">These sought their register among those that were reckoned by genealogy, but they were not found, therefore were they, as polluted</P>, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">put from the priesthood</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
As we can see, because of the lack of genealogical registry, they were cast out of the priesthood, even though according to tradition they were the sons of priests. These that had living witnesses of being sons of Aaron, but did not have the written genealogy, were persons that thought in good faith that they were from the family of the priesthood but were not admitted. It is good to note that these who were cast from the priesthood because of not having genealogy were not persons whose ancestors were lost due to a remote period. They were persons whose fathers and grandfathers lived 70 years earlier, when the first Temple was destroyed. However, not even in that case were they allowed to be priests and the ones that already were priests, were put out.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Well, the Second Temple was destroyed by the Roman armies almost two thousand years ago and with that all the genealogy and the nation. Never again were there genealogies in Israel. It is more evident that today <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">no one</P> <P ss="1" b="1">has proof of having been from the descendants of Aaron</P>, being that almost two thousand years have passed and not seventy.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Those aspiring to be priests in the future third temple do not have the demonstrative genealogythat authenticates the descendents of Aaron. They cannot even demonstrate if they are or not from Israel, their tradition is lost throughout the nebulous centuries. People who in the past have mixed in with the nation of Israel cannot be detected. Above all the Israelites of the tribes of Simeon, Benjamin, Efrain, Manasseh, etc.. In addition, Egyptians, Edomites, Romans, etc., without forgetting the Europeans in general who have been mixed throughout the centuries with the Jews of today. It is to say, that not only today no Jew knows what tribe he is a descendant of, but he doesn’t even know if he is a descendant of some of the foreigners who a thousand, two thousand or four thousand years ago mixed with the Jews. This way, even less would a Jew of today know if he is a descendant of Aaron. And if no one can prove that he descends from Aaron, no one can be a priest in the future third temple as invented by them, because there is no divine backing and order as in the two previous Temples.
</Paragraph>

<Section title="The future Jewish priesthood will be illegitimate as there are no genealogies">
<Paragraph>
 Even those whose last name is “Cohen”, cannot demonstrate by way of genealogy that they are truly descendants of Levi. Those names could have been adopted in past centuries for the sake of mere personal convenience, by any Jew who was from another tribe or anyone who, without being Jewish could have infiltrated himself among them. As we previously saw, the ones that were named Barzillai the Gileadite and others were cast from the priesthood.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">It is evident that these contradictions are shouting out to the ears of every Jew</P>, who do not cover their ears, that the Messiah, the True Lamb of God, has already come. These contradictions are shouting out to their ears, that Jesus Christ was the lamb symbolized from the lambs of different rituals and ceremonies. That he was the Messiah and to reject him is an affront towards God.
</Paragraph>
</Section>

<Section title="The absence of the Temple is a warning that God separated Himself from them">
<Paragraph>
 In the passage below I present that God warns the nation of Israel that if they separate from Him, the Temple would be destroyed. Therefore, the absence of the Temple indicates that they separated themselves from God.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="II Chr 7:19-20">
<Verse verse="19">
But if ye turn away, and forsake my statutes and my commandments, which I have set before you, and shall go and serve other gods, and worship them,
</Verse>
<Verse verse="20">
then will I pluck them up by the roots <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">out of my land</P> which I have given them, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">and this house, which I have sanctified for my name, will I cast out of my sight</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and will make it to be a proverb and a byword among all nations</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
The First Temple was destroyed and the Jews were rooted out of the land by Nebuchadnezzar, King of Babylon because Israel separated itself from God. <P ss="1" b="1" se="1">How did Israel separate itself from God this first time?</P> They did so by worshiping images. The Jews returned from Babylonian captivity and by mandate from God constructed the Second Temple. As is logical, for that Second Temple, the warning in the recently read passage was also valid: if they once again separated themselves from God, the Second Temple would also be destroyed.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Precisely</P>, the Second Temple was also destroyed and the Jews were rooted out of the land again, this time by Rome, a second “Babylon”, because the Jews once again separated themselves from God. <P ss="1" b="1" se="1">What did they do this second time to separate themselves from God?</P> God sent His Messiah, but the Jews rejected Him and therefore separated themselves from God. As a consequence, the Second Temple was destroyed and the Jews returned to captivity, same as when they separated themselves from God upon the destruction of the First Temple.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1" u="1">If their separation from God had not been motivated by their rejection of Jesus Christ as the Messiah</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">then, what other great sin did the nation of Israel commit this time</P>, that God punished them so severely, destroying the Second Temple and hurling them to a diaspora much worse than that of the 70 Babylonian years? The absence of the Temple and the prolonged diaspora, declare without words, but very seriously and eloquently, that Jesus is the Messiah, the Son of God.
</Paragraph>
</Section>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 8">
<Paragraph>
For the same reason as the mix of other nations with the nation of Israel and because of the absence of genealogy, something we saw in the preceding chapter, it is that today we cannot know if someone who says is a descendant of Aaron he truly is. The law of Moses was extremely strict in not allowing men who could not prove by way of genealogy that they were descendants of Aaron, to be priests. That is why as we saw previously in Ezra 2:59-62, those that alleged to be descendants of Aaron were cast out even though their genealogies has only been lost for 70 years, even that they claim to be Aaron’s descendants. People who have lost their genealogy for 2000 years are even less authorized to take on the task of the priesthood, even if they have adopted the name “Cohen”.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
All of these contradictions are screaming out to the ears of all those who do not want to cover them that the Messiah already arrived. It is clear that the true Lamb of God was sacrificed, which was symbolized by the lamb sacrifices. Therefore, there is no need for a Temple, nor sacrifices, nor priests. Any temple or sacrifice that is established in Jerusalem will be spurious, not authentic, illegitimate, and will not enjoy the blessings of God, but the usurpation of the antiChrist.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
As we previously saw, the absence of the Temple was a sign that the Jewish nation had separated themselves from God. The first separation from God was punished by the destruction of the First Temple by Nebuchadnezzar and the expulsion from their land for 70 years, and its cause was idolatry. The second separation from God occurred by having rejected the Messiah, the chosen one of God and was punished by the destruction of the Temple by the Romans and the expulsion from their land for almost 2000 years. If this was not the cause, what other great sin committed the nation to be so severely punished?
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
