<Chapter
  chapter="1"
  title="Demonstration that Jesus Christ is the Messiah that Hebrews await"
>
    <Paragraph bold="true">Why I wrote this book</Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    Whoever is a sincere believer and who thinks that his belief is the only correct believe, or even just better, has a duty to proclaim them for the benefit of others. He should propagate his faith. He should not “feed himself” alone without considering what will happen eternally to others.
    <P ss="1" b="1">To silence our beliefs is a form of cruel selfishness</P>
    , since by doing so we are condemning those who do not have a faith that saves for all eternity. Whoever does not proclaim his faith, it is because he despises other human beings, because his fellow human beings and their eternal destiny does not matter to him, or because in reality he is not sure that his belief is true or better. It is just as simple as that. This is why I present my faith to everyone, including Jewish people.
    </Paragraph>


    <Paragraph>
    <P se="1" b="1">The purpose of this book is to help all Hebrews of good faith to verify that Jesus Christ is the Messiah.</P>
    I do it so that while verifying this, they can find salvation for their souls by accepting him as the Lamb of God that takes away the sins of the world.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    Abraham, Isaac, Jacob, Moses and the other patriarchs sacrificed a lamb to atone for their sins. They did this because God revealed that He would send the Messiah that would be the True Lamb of God that would take away the sins of the world.
        </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    Today some benighted folks regard the sacrifice of lambs for the pardon of sins that faithful Jews did during the epochs before the destruction of the Temple by the Romans, to be barbaric. This was not savagery, but rather symbolism for what they knew would occur some day in the future. The Lamb of God was Jesus Christ. This is why after His sacrifice God permitted the destruction of the Temple that put an end to the sacrifice of lambs in the Temple forever.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
   <P se="1" b="1">The purpose of this book is to demonstrate that Jesus is the Messiah, the True Lamb of God, to the Jews that believe in the writings of Moses and the prophets.</P>
    I do not base this on the writings of the “wise,” but rather on the Hebrew Scriptures, that is, the Old Testament. I am not using the opinion of priests, rabbis or pastors, those who are regarded as “wise” by their followers. The only Wise One is our Creator who gave us the Scriptures of the prophets to guide us in our behavior and to reach the knowledge about <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">who</P> the wished for Messiah <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">will be</P> and <P ss="1" b="1">when He will come</P>. If we read the Scriptures, we will see that the Messiah is to have two comings to the Earth. One as a lamb to be sacrificed for the sins of those that love God; another as the King of the World, to govern with a rod of iron. The First Coming has already occurred with the birth, life without sin, crucifixion, death and resurrection of Jesus. The Second Coming is yet to happen, and does not seem far off in coming.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    When a person in good faith believes that he has found a truth that could benefit others, his duty is to share it. This is what I am doing.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    <P se="1" b="1">God has not given us the Scriptures so that we have to depend on others to understand them.</P>
    The Creator gives His Word so that any human being can understand it, a wise man as well as a fisherman. Just the same, as always happens, some folks take advantage of the situation and try to get us to believe that if it is not through his “superior intellect” or through his “divine anointing,” we, who are simple mortals, cannot find out what God expects of us.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    <P b="1">On the day that we face the Final Judgment</P>, we will not be asked what our pastors, rabbis or priests taught us, but rather what did the Holy Scriptures say. This is why in this book there will be no mention of the opinion of any rabbi, priest, pastor or “wise” theologian. Instead we will depend only on what the true prophets of God said.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    In general the clergy of all the religions “live off of their story,” and charge us a lot to “teach” what they assert is the product of “wisdom” and much study. God gives all of the humans an opportunity to search for the truth; we do not have to rely on others.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    <P se="1" b="1">My counsel to all who read this book is to look for the Hebrew Scriptures (Old Testament) written in Hebrew</P> and printed with the seal of the orthodox by orthodox printers, to substantiate the truthfulness of the arguments that are written here. Do not use modern language translations, because when the translators come to those passages that show that Jesus is the Messiah, their special interests tend to cause them to distort the translation. What has been written in Hebrew is not
    distorted, especially the ancient manuscripts found in the libraries.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    There are several reasons why the ancient texts are dependable.
    <P ss="1" b="1">First</P>, the Jews that are true believers have not permitted to distort the Word of God when recording it.
    <P ss="1" b="1">Second</P>, those that make
    translations from the Hebrew to English, Spanish or any other language are not afraid that their distortions will be discovered because those that know Hebrew do not read these altered translations, and those that do not know Hebrew cannot challenge the translation.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    <P b="1">Where I worked, there was a fellow worker, a Biophysics scientist, who was a Hebrew Sabra</P>, that is, someone who was born and raised in Israel. This is why he read and understood Hebrew perfectly well. The man was not religious, was not interested in these questions and really had no prejudicial opinion. Since both of us spoke English, he translated what I asked about to English.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    <P b="1">I had an Old Testament written in Hebrew</P>, that a now deceased Jewish friend had given me. He brought it from Israel. When I wanted to see if whether a passage in the Old Testament translated in the Reina-Valera [the principal translation of the Scriptures to Spanish] was the same in Hebrew, I photocopied the passage in my Hebrew Scripture and took it to my companion, asking him to translate it to English.
    <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">Every time</P> that he did it, what this Jewish Sabra said harmonized with the Reina-Valera in Spanish and differed from the rabbinical translations to Spanish in Argentina. This is why I counsel you to use the ancient Hebrew Scriptures if you know Hebrew. Or, use the method that I used, find a Sabra who is not religious and use him to translate without bias the passages you are interested in.
    </Paragraph>

    <Section title="Why is every line in this book numbered?">
    <Paragraph>
    To my way of seeing things, every writer should be accessible to healthy and edifying discussion, and not enclosed in his “ivory tower” without permitting debates on his theory. This is why I give access to those who oppose what I say, because I consider that the light comes out of healthy debate. This way I benefit because those errors I might have are corrected, and my interlocutors benefit because they can drop any errors they may have.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
   None of the authors I have known has wished to dispute his doctrines or interpretations of the Scriptures in writing. What they say is to be believed dogmatically; because “magister dixit.” And if one tries to challenge what they teach with written reasons and arguments, these “authorities” reply saying that they do not want to “waste their time” because they are “very busy.” This way they avoid being shown to be in error.
   </Paragraph>
    </Section>

    <Section title="Summary of Chapter 1">
    <Paragraph>
    Whoever is a believer in good faith and considers that his religion is the only right one, or the best, should proclaim it for the benefit of others. The purpose of this book is to help all of the Hebrews of good faith to prove that Jesus is the Messiah, the Lamb of God. This is how their souls can be saved.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    On the day that we face the Final Judgment, we will not be asked about what our pastors, rabbis or priests taught, but rather what the Holy Scriptures say.
    </Paragraph>

    <Paragraph>
    Since I do not know the Hebrew language, I availed myself of a Jewish Sabra that worked with me. He was not religious and translated without prejudices. I recommend that you do something similar.
    </Paragraph>
    </Section>
</Chapter>
