<Chapter chapter="11" title="Prophesies of the Old and the New Testament indicate to us that the Jews would convert to Christ in final times">
<Paragraph>
When the prophet Hosea says: “<P i="1">For the children of Israel shall abide many days without a king</P>…etc.”, <P ss="1" b="1">he is undoubtedly referring to the period of the diaspora and not the captivity of Babylon</P>, because he is talking about the end of days. In addition, there were still prophets and princes during the period of Babylon. Only the diaspora is in concordance with this description of the prophet Hosea, because during the centuries of the diaspora there were never high priests nor did they worship idols
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Hos 3:4-5">
<Verse verse="4">
For <P ss="1" b="1">the children of Israel shall abide many days without a king, and without a prince, and without a sacrifice, and without an image</P>, and without an ephod, and without teraphim.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="5">
<P se="1" b="1">Afterward</P> shall the children of Israel return, and <P ss="1" b="1">seek the LORD their God</P>, <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">and David their king</P>; and shall fear the LORD and his goodness <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">in the latter days</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
We should note that it is said that <P ss="1" se="1" u="1" b="1">after</P> that period in which they would find themselves without priests, nor sacrifices, etc., it adds that they would seek the Lord their God and <P ss="1" b="1">David, their king</P>. From this, we realize that <P ss="1" b="1">they are talking about the Messiah; because the true King David had already died</P>, there was no way of seeking him. In addition, we should notice that it says that this would occur “<P i="1" b="1">in the latter days</P>”. From that statement we can come to the conclusion that the Jews, in the end of days, would convert to Christ.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In the New Testament there are also prophecies that point out the future conversion of the Jews towards Christ. One of them is Saint Paul’s in which he symbolically compares the Jews to the olive tree and the gentiles (goyim) to a wild olive tree. Let’s see.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ro 11:17-26">
<Verse verse="17">
And if some of the branches be broken off, and thou, being a wild olive tree, wert graffed in among them, and with them partakest of the root and fatness of the olive tree;
</Verse>

<Verse verse="18">
boast not against the branches. But if thou boast, thou bearest not the root, but the root thee.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="19">
Thou wilt say then: The branches were broken off, that I might be graffed in.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="20">
Well; <P ss="1" b="1">because of unbelief they were broken off</P>, and thou standest by faith. Be not highminded, but fear.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="21">
For if God spared not the natural branches, take heed lest he also spare not thee.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="22">
Behold therefore the goodness and severity of God: on them which fell, severity; but toward thee, goodness, if thou continue in his goodness, otherwise thou also shalt be cut off.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="23">
<P b="1">And they also, if they abide not still in unbelief, shall be graffed in</P>, <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">for God is able to graff them in again</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="24">
For if thou wert cut out of the olive tree which is wild by nature, and wert graffed contrary to nature into a good olive tree, <P ss="1" b="1">how much more shall these, which be the natural branches, be graffed into their own olive tree?</P>
</Verse>

<Verse verse="25">
For I would not, brethren, that ye should be ignorant of this mystery, lest ye should be wise in your own conceits; that blindness in part is happened to Israel, until the fullness of the Gentiles be come in.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="26">
<P u="1" b="1">And so all Israel shall be saved</P>, as it is written: There shall come out of Sion the Deliverer, and shall turn away ungodliness from Jacob.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
As we can see, in the prophecies of the Old Testament as in the New Testament, exist the announcement that in the end of days, the Jews would convert to Jesus Christ, as their personal savior. The Lamb of God, who cleanses the sins, as symbolized by the lambs sacrificed in the Temple, will at last be accepted.
</Paragraph>

<Section title="The Messiah would come twice: once as the Lamb of God and the other as the King of the Earth">
<Paragraph>
Upon reading the prophecies in the Old Testament as well as the New Testament, we find that the Messiah was going to come twice: <P ss="1" b="1">the first</P>, when He would come to suffer for our sins, and <P ss="1" b="1">the second coming</P>, when He would come to reign with an iron rod. <P ss="1" b="1">The first coming</P>, in which he would suffer for our sins, is prophesized in the 52 and 53 chapters of Isaiah. <P ss="1" b="1">The second coming</P>, when he will rule the earth is prophesized in various passages, in which I chose Psalm 2:8-9 and Psalm 110:1-2. Let’s see.
</Paragraph>

<Cite wrap="true" cite="Isa 52:13 to 53:12">
<Verse verse="Isa 52:13">
<P se="1" b="1">Behold, my servant</P> shall deal prudently, he shall be exalted and extolled, and be very high.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="14">
As many were astonied at thee; his visage was so marred more than any man, and his form more than the sons of men.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="15">
<P b="1">So shall he sprinkle many nations</P>; the kings shall shut their mouths at him, for that which had not been told them shall they see; and that which they had not heard shall they consider.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="53:1">
<P se="1" b="1">Who hath believed our report?</P> And to whom is the arm of the LORD revealed?
</Verse>

<Verse verse="2">
For he shall grow up before him as a tender plant, and as a root out of a dry ground. He hath no form nor comeliness; and when <P ss="1" b="1">we shall see him, there is no beauty that we should desire him</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="3">
<P b="1">He is despised and rejected of men</P>; a man of sorrows, and acquainted with grief. <P ss="1" b="1">And we hid as it were our faces from him</P>; <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">he was despised</P>, and <P ss="1" b="1">we esteemed him not</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="4">
<P b="1">Surely he hath borne our griefs, and carried our sorrows</P>, yet we did esteem him stricken, smitten of God, and afllicted.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="5">
<P b="1">But he was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities</P>, the chastisement of our peace was upon him; and with his stripes we are healed.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="6">
All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and <P ss="1" b="1">the LORD hath laid on him the iniquity of us all</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="7">
He was oppressed, and he was afllicted, yet he opened not his mouth; he is brought <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">as a lamb</P> to the slaughter, and <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">as a sheep</P> before her shearers is dumb, so he openeth not his mouth.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="8">
He was taken from prison and from judgment; and who shall declare his generation? <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">For he was cut off out of the land of the living</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">for the transgression of my people was he stricken</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="9">
<P b="1">And he made his grave with the wicked, and with the rich in his death</P>; because he had done no violence, neither was any deceit in his mouth.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="10">
Yet it pleased the LORD to bruise him; he hath put him to grief. <P ss="1" b="1">When thou shalt make his soul an offering for sin, he shall see his seed</P>, <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">he shall prolong his days</P>, and the pleasure of the LORD shall prosper in his hand.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="11">
He shall see of the travail of his soul, and shall be satisfied. By his knowledge <P ss="1" b="1">shall my righteous servant justify many</P>; <P ss="1" b="1">for he shall bear their iniquities</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="12">
Therefore will I divide him a portion with the great, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong; because <P ss="1" b="1">he hath poured out his soul</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">unto death</P>, and he was numbered with the transgressors; and <P ss="1" b="1">he bare the sin of many</P>, and made intercession for the transgressors.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Up to this point we see the prophecy of his First Coming</P>. Let’s see now in Psalm 2, where we see that it is referring to the Messiah. In this context, it says that <P ss="1" b="1">He would rule over the people with a rod of iron</P>, that is, He is not coming like the first time to allow himself to be crucified, spit upon, beaten, etc., for our sins. Being that our sins are already cleansed by the acceptance of his sacrifice, He does not have to return to suffer, but to govern. That is why the prophecy says:
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 2:8-9">
<Verse verse="8">
Ask of me, and I shall give thee the heathen for thine inheritance, and the uttermost parts of the Earth for thy possession.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="9">
Thou shalt break them <P ss="1" b="1">with a rod of iron</P>; thou shalt dash them in pieces like a potter's vessel
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
We also have this other of David’s Psalms and a passage from the prophet Zechariah:
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ps 110:1-2">
<Verse verse="1">
<P u="1" b="1">A Psalm of David</P>. The LORD said unto my Lord: Sit thou at my right hand, <P ss="1" b="1">until I make</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">thine enemies thy footstool</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="2">
The LORD shall send the rod of thy strength out of Zion, <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">rule</P> <P ss="1" b="1">thou in the midst of thine enemies</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Zechariah 12:8-10">
<Verse verse="8">
In that day shall the LORD defend the inhabitants of Jerusalem; and he that is feeble among them at that day shall be as David; and the house of David shall be as God, as the angel of the LORD before them.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="9">
And it shall come to pass in that day, that I will seek to destroy all the nations that come against Jerusalem.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="10">
And I will pour upon the house of David, and upon the inhabitants of Jerusalem, the spirit of grace and of supplications, and <P ss="1" b="1">they shall look upon me whom</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">they have pierced</P>, and they shall mourn for him, as one mourneth for his only son, and shall be in bitterness for him, as one that is in bitterness for his firstborn.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
As we have seen, there are two types of clear references about the coming of the Messiah. <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">The first</P> type of references, as the Lamb of God to take away the sin of those who accept Him. <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">The second</P> type, as the King of the Earth to impose justice.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Dear Reader, do not be one of those who reject the salvation that Jesus Christ, the Lamb sent by God offers you</P>. Do not become threatened by the fact that if you convert to Jesus Christ, those that share in same religion as you will call you “marrano”, or will erase you from their book of friends. It is worse for God to erase you from the Book of Life. <P ss="1" b="1">Religions that have to be imposed with pressures, vendettas or brute force, are not of God</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
If in order to “look good” with them, you go towards perdition, when you are in Hell, none of those “friends” who now sing praises if you do not convert to Christ, will be able to help you in anything. Accept Jesus Christ, the Lamb of God, who is He whose blood cleans your sins, and liberate yourself from Hell, as symbolized by the ritual sacrifices in the Temple.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
If at the end of days, many Jews will accept Jesus Christ, be one of the first and not one of the last.
</Paragraph>
</Section>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 11">
<Paragraph>
Various prophesies of the Old and New Testament indicate that the Jews will accept Christ in the end of days. Perhaps during the last of the seventy weeks of the prophet Daniel. In the Old Testament, in Hosea 3:4-5, we see such a thing, and later in the New Testament in Romans 11:17-26.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Let us remember Psalm 2 in which we see that it is referring to the Messiah. In that context, it says that He will rule with a rod of iron. Therefore, He is not coming as the first time allowing himself to be crucified, spit upon, beaten, etc., for our sins. This second time He is coming to rule, to put the world in order and impose true justice. That will be the Second Coming of Christ, this time he will come in the clouds. <P ss="1" b="1">Remember this that I say to you, because it is a life or death issue</P>: <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">if He does not come from the clouds, he is not the true Messiah</P>. That was what Prophet Daniel announced in 7:13- 14, when he said that <P ss="1" b="1">the one to whom was going to be given all power in the whole world (the Messiah) was to come in the clouds of heaven</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Dn 7: 13-14">
<Verse verse="13">
I saw in the night visions, and, <P ss="1" b="1">behold, one like the Son of man</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">came with the clouds of heaven</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">and came to the Ancient of days, and they brought him near before him</P>.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="14">
<P u="1" b="1">And there was given him dominion, and glory, and a kingdom, that all people, nations, and languages, should serve him; his dominion is an everlasting dominion, which shall not pass away, and his kingdom that which shall not be destroyed</P>.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
Remember, <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">if he does not come in the clouds, he is not the true Messiah</P>, he is an impostor, probably the antiChrist. Don’t forget, because <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">it is a matter of life or death, a matter of salvation or eternal damnation</P>.
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
