<Chapter  lang="en" chapter="10" title="Slandering Christ is easier than reading Scripture, but more dangerous to the slanderer">
<Paragraph>
 I have frequently argued with some of my Jewish friends, that because of being educated under the rabbinical influence, they have assured me that Jesus said he was the son of God, because he did not have a recognized father and among the Jews being a bastard is a very grave stain. That is why, according to them, his defense was to say, when asked about his father, that he was the son of God, one of the sons, as with any other human. However, that is false because the entire town knew him as the son of the carpenter.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In addition, the most elementary logic tells us that if there would have been the smallest suspicion that Christ was a bastard, his fellow believers and <P ss="1" b="1">above all his enemies of the religious elite</P>, would have not allowed him to go the Temple, or belong to the synagogue, they would have expelled him, and they would not have allowed him to teach in the synagogue. The law of God prohibited bastards from belonging to the congregation, as it is seen in Deuteronomy 23:2.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Deuteronomy 23:2">
<Verse>
<P b="1">A bastard shall not enter into the congregation of the LORD</P>; even to his tenth generation shall he not enter into the congregation of the LORD.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Cite cite="Matthew 13:54-57">
<Verse verse="54">
<P b="1">And</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">when he was come into his own country</P>, <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">he taught them in their synagogue</P>, insomuch that they were astonished, and said: Whence hath this man this wisdom, and these mighty works?
</Verse>

<Verse verse="55">
<P b="1">Is not this the</P> <P ss="1" u="1" b="1">carpenter’s son?</P> <P ss="1" b="1">Is not his mother called Mary? And his brethren, James, and Joses, and Simon, and Judas?</P>
</Verse>

<Verse verse="56">
<P se="1" b="1">And his sisters, are they not all with us?</P> Whence then hath this man all these things?
</Verse>

<Verse verse="57">
And they were offended in him. But Jesus said unto them: A prophet is not without honour, save in his own country, and in his own house.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
As it is seen in this passage <P ss="1" b="1">he was considered the son of the carpenter</P> <P ss="1" se="1" u="1" b="1">by the entire town</P> and in addition, knew his entire family. Therefore, Jesus was not confronted with the social problem of being a son without a father, a bastard, as some rabbis have slandered. Slander was easier than using common sense as seen in Isaiah 7:14; Isaiah 53; Daniel 9:24-27, etc..
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Don’t anyone respond that the verse Matthew 13:55 is a lie placed there to distort the case of him being a bastard, because if the writer would have wanted to lie, they would not have written that Jesus was <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">not</P> a direct son of Joseph. They could have said that he was his carnal son, but with the intervention of the Spirit of God. When all the things that have been said in Scripture is said, without omitting any, it is because, primarily they are telling the truth and secondly because they don’t care what others say or think
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
I have tried to take those Jewish friends away from their error with this reasoning on one hand, and on the other, <P ss="1" b="1">showing the many prophecies about Christ as the Messiah as there is in the Old Testament</P>. The problem is that the rabbis, as the Catholic hierarchy and many other sects that are not Catholic, emphasize that their parishioners go to the synagogue and leave money; but very little in the reading of Scripture by their followers themselves.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">The majority of the most religious</P> only read a portion of the Torah (Pentateuch) each Sabbath in the synagogue... and that is all. They never read the prophets, Psalms, etc.. They ignore most of it. Instead of the Old Testament, they read the Talmud to them and a series of rabbinical books. These books, like those of all religious elites, do not teach about God, but they only aspire to maintain themselves in the position of influence and dominance
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Look throughout each synagogue, to see if you find a Jew who has read the complete Old Testament at least twenty times in his life. The great majority have not completely read it once. If you are not interested in the word of God, how can you find the truth?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Those who dare to slander the Messiah are playing with fire, because they are knowingly transgressing the ninth commandment, and they are transgressing against God and His Messiah.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Ex 20:16">
<Verse>
Thou shalt not bear false witness against thy neighbour.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 10">
<Paragraph>
There are Jews who slander Christ by saying that he was a bastard son. The law of God prohibited a bastard son to belong to the synagogue. If there would have been the slightest suspicion that Christ was a bastard, his fellow believers and above all his enemies of the religious elite would not have allowed him to belong to the synagogue, and much less teach there or enter the Temple. The whole town knew Christ as the son of the carpenter.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Those who dare to slander the Messiah are playing with the fires of Hell because knowingly they are transgressing the ninth commandment and are doing so against God and His Messiah.
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
