<Chapter chapter="4" title="Malachi, the prophet, warned that the Messiah would enter this Temple and that He would have a precursor just as Haggai prophesied">

<Paragraph>
 The next verse announces that God would send his messenger to prepare the way, and
 <P ss="1" b="1">that after this, the Lord that the Jews were seeking would suddenly come to His Temple (the very same Temple that Malachi knew)</P>.
 The one who was to come was the same messenger of the covenant, the delight of the Jews. Here is the passage:
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Mal 3:1">
<Verse>
Behold,
<P ss="1" b="1">I will send my messenger</P>,
and he shall prepare the way
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">before me</P>;
<P ss="1" b="1">and</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the Lord, whom ye seek</P>,
<P ss="1" b="1">shall suddenly come to</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">his</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">Temple</P>,
even the messenger of the covenant, whom ye delight in. Behold, he shall come, saith the LORD of hosts.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
To judge by what is prophesied here,
<P ss="1" b="1">a precursor messenger would be sent first, and then the Messiah would enter that Temple</P>,
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">and not another one</P>.
Everyone knows that John the Baptist, who came with the spirit and virtue of Elijah, preceded Jesus, preparing the masses who for centuries had not seen a prophet, for the coming of Jesus.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">What other person of messianic stature entered that Temple and was preceded by a powerful messenger like John the Baptist?</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">No one</P>.
Therefore if Jesus is not the Messiah, like many Jews think today, then the prophecy has failed miserably, which is a ridiculous absurdity and is unbelievable for any believing Jew.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">What other person with messianic stature, apart from Christ</P>,
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">entered that very Temple? Who else has been preceded in his ministry by a precursor messenger of the stature of John the Baptist?</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">And who else</P>
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">combines the personal characteristics and circumstances that were predicted in Daniel 9 and Isaiah 52-53 and that were to characterize the Messiah?</P>
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1" u="1">All of this agrees with what Haggai the prophet said</P> in Haggai 2:6-9.
<P ss="1" b="1">Also he predicted that the Messiah would enter that Temple</P>, and for that reason the glory of that Temple would be greater than that of the first Temple, despite the fact that the first one (Solomon’s Temple) had greater riches. Even though the Second Temple was less important from a human perspective and was not as richly decorated as the First Temple, it could only obtain greater glory (as Haggai 2:6-9 says), because it was visited by <P ss="1" b="1">“the desire of all nations”</P> and <P ss="1" b="1">“the Lord, whom ye seek.”</P>
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
That is why God says in Haggai 2:8, “The silver is mine, and the gold is mine”, as if to say that if I wanted to fill the Second Temple with gold and silver it would not be difficult at all for me, but that will not happen, its greater glory will consist of being the place that the Messiah will visit.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Despite all of these proofs and clarity, there are now a number of “wise linguists” with a lot of pretensions of being “sincere” and “objective” translators that want to alter the translation.
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">They say that the word “desired” that for centuries has appeared in all of the translations is incorrect. According to them, the word should be “riches” instead.</P>
In other words instead of the passage saying: “…the desire of all nations” the text should say “. . .the wealth of all the nations…”
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In their eagerness to make an “ecumenical” Bible, they are trying to make us see that instead of “the desire of all nations” (which the passage has always said and is <P ss="1" b="1">what the Hebrew says</P>), that what is coming to the temple is the wealth of all the nations.” You can see how they want to annul a prophecy that irrefutably demonstrates that Jesus Christ is the Messiah. The text says:
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Hag 2:6-9">
<Verse verse="6">
For thus saith the LORD of hosts: <P ss="1" b="1">Yet once, it is a little while, and I will shake the</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">heavens, and the Earth</P>, and the sea, and the
dry land;
</Verse>

<Verse verse="7">
and I will shake all nations, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">and the desire of all nations shall come</P>; and <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">I will fill this house with glory</P>, saith the LORD of hosts.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="8">
<P b="1">The silver is mine, and the gold is mine</P>, saith the LORD of hosts.
</Verse>

<Verse verse="9">
<P b="1">The glory of this latter house shall be greater than of the former</P>, saith the LORD of hosts. And in this place will I give peace, saith the LORD of hosts.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
If you read this passage in the Hebrew of the ancient Jewish Orthodox text, you will see that it is “the desired one” and not “the wealth” which the prophecy mentions. But even without verifying the ancient orthodox version in Hebrew, using the simplest common sense, you can see which is right.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1" u="1">In the first place</P> logic tells us that “the desire of the nations” can come by himself,
<P ss="1" b="1" u="1">he is coming</P>
<P ss="1" b="1">on his own accord</P>; but “the wealth of the nations” <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">could not come on its own</P>, somebody has to <P ss="1" se="1" b="1" u="1">bring</P> it. Apparently the folks who want to alter the word for “desire” forgot to change the verb “come” to “bring”.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1" u="1">Secondly</P>, if Haggai, who lived before the birth of Christ, <P ss="1" b="1">was referring to Jesus when he said that the “desire of the nations” would come to the Temple, he was right in his prophecy</P>.
In fact, <P ss="1" b="1">the Messiah did come to the Second Temple and filled it with glory</P>.
But if the text reads as these modern, suspicious “linguists” want, then <P ss="1" b="1">Haggai’s prophecy failed miserably by referring to “the wealth of the nations” that came</P>.
The “wealth of the nations” did not come nor was brought to the Temple nor did it fill the Temple with glory, <P ss="1" b="1">nor did the world tremble because of the wealth of the Temple</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">It was Rome that took the riches</P> of the people in that epoch. This Temple was destroyed in the year 70, A.D. and the wealth of the nations was never brought to the Temple. Therefore, if we allow ourselves to be guided by these suspicious translators and “experts” in the Hebrew language, we have to conclude that Haggai failed and that whoever inspired him also failed which is absurd for any true believer.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
However, if we are guided by the translators that came before the modern ecumenism, those that always translated the text as, “the desire of the nations”, we can verify that the prophecy has been fulfilled because:
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">a)</P> The “desire of the nations” (the Messiah) came to this Temple before it was destroyed
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">b)</P> The world was shaken at the coming of the Christ.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">c)</P> With His coming, the Temple, that was being built at the time of the prophecy and that Haggai referred to, was glorified.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">d)</P> The glory of the Second Temple was greater than that of the first because the Messiah came to it and not to the first Temple.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
If the prophesied glory was not the result of the coming of the Messiah to the Second Temple, then in what other way was the glory of the Second Temple greater than that of the Temple that the great king Solomon constructed and filled with riches?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1" u="1">Thirdly</P>, we see that if this passage translates the word “desire” as it has always been translated, then it agrees with Malachi 3:1 that announces the same thing. However, if the word is translated as “wealth”, it does not agree with any other passage of the Old Testament and becomes uniquely isolated and unconnected.
</Paragraph>

<Cite cite="Mal 3:1">
<Verse>
Behold, I will send my messenger, and he shall prepare the way before me; and <P ss="1" b="1">the Lord, whom ye seek, shall suddenly come to his Temple</P>, even the messenger of the covenant, whom ye delight in. Behold, he shall come, saith the LORD of hosts.
</Verse>
</Cite>

<Paragraph>
Since it was the Second Temple that the prophet referred to, the one with less importance from the human point of view, and with less riches, it is only possible to attribute to it greater glory if, as the prophet Haggai says, “the desire of the nations” (Haggai 2:7) and “the Lord whom ye seek” (Malachi 3:1) came.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
This is why God says in Haggai 2:8, “The silver is mine, and the gold is mine, saith the LORD of hosts”; as if to say that if He wanted to fill the Second Temple with gold and silver, it would be no problem at all. But that was not to be, because the greater glory consisted in receiving the Messiah into the Temple.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1" u="1">Fourth</P>, the reason the translators present their <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">fairy tale</P> is to weaken the prophecy of the Messiah. Their fairy tale states that the Second Temple was constructed by Herod, or at least enlarged by Herod to the point that it became greater and better than Solomon’s Temple. They invent this fiction in order to “demonstrate” that the Second Temple was greater and richer than the first. This is how they try to bend Haggai’s prophecy so that it agrees with an unreal “reality”.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P se="1" b="1">It is absurd to think that Herod</P> was going to be able to spend more on the second Temple and give it greater riches than an independent and powerful king like <P ss="1" b="1">Solomon</P>. Herod could not dedicate more wealth to the Temple than Solomon because:
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">a)</P> He was a third-class kinglet that only governed <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">a small section</P> <P ss="1" b="1">of Judea</P>,
<P ss="1" b="1">b)</P> he was a vassal of Rome, a kinglet that was dependent on Rome for tax collections and had to send there the riches,
<P ss="1" b="1">c)</P> on the other hand, Solomon possessed enormous riches, <P ss="1" se="1" b="1">he governed all of the territory of Israel</P> as well as the neighboring nations. He had a number of vassal kings that paid him tribute.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
That is a fairy tale to say that Herod gave the Second Temple greater riches than Solomon gave to the first; only the unreasoning would swallow that.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In addition to all of this, one must remember that
<P ss="1" se="1" b="1">God vetoed David’s wish to construct the First Temple</P>
because
<P ss="1" b="1">David had shed much blood</P>.
He suffered this veto despite the fact that most of the blood that he shed was generally in justified wars. Just the same, God did veto David’s project so that he did not construct the First Temple.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Can you believe that God vetoed David’s enterprise, but rewarded Herod’s? This kinglet was an assassin of children and adults. Was God going to reward him by granting Haggai’s prophecy that Herod was to construct a more glorious, bigger and better Temple than Solomon’s? Can you think that God was about to base the glory of the Second Temple in the riches and constructions made by an consummate assassin of the Hebrews? Would God veto David, a Hebrew, but approve Herod who in addition to being an assassin was an Edomite and not a Hebrew?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">Unfortunately there are many who are confused by these “experts” and that believe their fairy tales</P>. It is a lie to say that the riches of the nations came to rest in the Second Temple. On the contrary, it was the riches of the Second Temple that were dispersed to the nations, especially to Rome under the command of the Roman general Titus Flavius Vespasianus.
</Paragraph>

<Section title="Summary of Chapter 4">
<Paragraph>
The prophets Malachi and Haggai predicted that the Messiah would enter the Second Temple. The only person with messianic stature that entered that Temple was Jesus Christ, therefore it follows that He is the Messiah.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Indeed Malachi said that before the Messiah came a messenger from God would come. This was fulfilled by John the Baptist. And then Haggai said that the glory of the Second Temple that was being constructed would be greater than that of the first, because in it would come “the desire of the nations”, the Messiah. Only Jesus Christ fulfills this prophecy well.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In regards to Herod, an assassin, a vassal kinglet of Rome, it was impossible for him to construct a temple greater than the temple that the great King Solomon constructed. If God had denied David permission to construct the First Temple because of the blood he had shed, certainly He would not have granted the construction of a greater temple than Solomon’s to a vile assassin like Herod, nor would God tell Haggai to prophesy such thing.
</Paragraph>
</Section>
</Chapter>
