<Chapter chapter="6" title="Should a sincere worshiper of God change His laws without divine authorization? Passover">
<Paragraph>
 In all of the Old and New Testament, God warns very seriously that his commandments were not be changed. Unfortunately the great majority of the believers in God disregards this warning and changes the commandments. One of these changes, done without divine authorization is to make Sunday the day of rest instead of Saturday. This heresy is found in almost all of the Christian denominations. Another of these changes is the worshiping of the Virgin Mary and of the images of the saints which have been given the category of demi gods as in Catholicism and other so-called Christian religions. Here is what God warns us:
 </Paragraph>

 <Cite cite="Deut. 4:1-2">
 <Verse verse="1">
 Now therefore hearken, O Israel, unto the statutes and unto the judgments, which I teach you, for to do them, that ye may live, and go in and possess the land which the LORD God of your fathers giveth you.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="2">
 <P b="1">Ye</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">shall not add</P> <P ss="1" b="1">unto the word which I command you</P>, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">neither shall ve diminish ought from it</P>, that ye may keep the commandments of the LORD your God which I command you.
 </Verse>
 </Cite>

 <Cite cite="Deut. 12:32">
 <Verse>
 What thing soever I command you, observe to do it; <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">thou shalt not add thereto, nor diminish from it</P>.
 </Verse>
 </Cite>

 <Cite cite="Prv 30:6">
 <Verse>
 <P b="1" u="1">Add thou not unto his words, lest he reprove thee, and thou be found a liar</P>.
 </Verse>
 </Cite>

 <Cite cite="Rev 22:18-19">
 <Verse verse="18">
 For I testify unto every man that heareth the words of the prophecy of this book, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">If any man shall add</P> <P ss="1" b="1">unto these things, God shall add unto him the plagues that are written in this book</P>.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="19">
<P b="1">And</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">if any man shall take away from the words of the book of this prophecy</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">God shall take away his part out of the book of life, and out of the holy city, and from the things which are written in this book</P>.
 </Verse>
 </Cite>

 <Paragraph>
 As I was saying, almost all of the believers in God disregard or change His commandments and the Jews are no exception. Moses established, by God’s command, laws and ordinances that Judaism has dismissed or changed. <P ss="1" b="1">One of these is the celebration of Passover</P>. Let’s see what God commanded and what Judaism has done.
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 The Passover that the Jews celebrate today is a poor caricature of what God commanded through Moses. In general the same thing happens with their religion: It takes form from a group of superstitions without a biblical basis, without a basis in Moses, but rather is based on the rabbinical commandments.
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 In the passage that is found below, we see how the Passover was to be observed. And... what about the contemporary Judaism? Does it follow these commands? Certainly not as we shall see:
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">a)</P> They do not begin the year with the month of the Passover (around March and April). Instead it begins with Rosh Hashanah in September (verse 2).
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">b)</P> They do not separate out a lamb for each family on the 10th of the corresponding month (verse 3).
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">c)</P> They do not use a lamb which is one year old (verse 5).
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">d)</P> They do not sacrifice it on the fourteenth day in the afternoon for eating on this same night (verse 6).
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">e)</P> They do not anoint the side posts and upper door post with the blood of the lamb (verse 7).
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">f)</P> Some, rather than eating lamb eat turkey for example.
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">g)</P> They do not roast the whole lamb, nor eat the lamb with bitter herbs (verses 8-9)
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">h)</P> They do not burn the remains (verse 10)
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1" se="1">I)</P> They do not eat it in haste, as if they were to leave on a journey. Instead they make a feast and eat it unhurriedly (verse 11).
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 <P b="1">j)</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">And above all</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">they eat the Passover meal</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">outside of Jerusalem</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">something that is</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">expressly prohibited by God</P>. (Deut. 16:5-6). Let’s see.
 </Paragraph>

 <Cite cite="Ex 12:1-11">
 <Verse verse="1">
 And the LORD spake unto Moses and Aaron in the land of Egypt, saying:
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="2">
 <P b="1">This month shall be unto you</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the beginning of months</P>, <P ss="1" b="1">it shall be</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">the first month of the year</P> <P ss="1" b="1">to you</P>.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="3">
 Speak ye unto all the congregation of Israel, saying: <P ss="1" b="1">In the tenth day of this month they shall take to them every man a lamb</P>, according to the house of their fathers, <P ss="1" b="1">a lamb for an house</P>.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="4">
 And if the household be too little for the lamb, let him and his neighbour next unto his house take it according to the number of the souls; every man according to his eating shall make your count for the lamb.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="5">
 Your lamb shall be without blemish, <P ss="1" b="1">a male of the first year</P>; ye shall take it out from the sheep, or from the goats.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="6">
 And ye shall keep it up until <P ss="1" b="1">the fourteenth day</P> of the same month; and <P ss="1" b="1">the whole assembly of the congregation</P> of Israel shall kill it in the evening.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="7">
 <P b="1" se="1">And they shall take of the blood, and strike it on the two side posts and on the upper door post of the houses</P>, wherein they shall eat it.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="8">
 <P b="1" se="1">And they shall eat the flesh in that night, roast with fire</P>, and unleavened bread; <P ss="1" b="1">and with bitter herbs they shall eat it</P>.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="9">
 Eat not of it raw, nor sodden at all with water, but roast with fire; his head with his legs, and with the purtenance thereof.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="10">
 And ye shall let nothing of it remain until the morning; <P ss="1" b="1">and that which remaineth of it until the morning ye shall burn with fire</P>.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="11">
 And thus shall ye eat it; with your loins girded, your shoes on your feet, and your staff in your hand; and <P ss="1" b="1">ye shall eat it in haste</P>: it is the LORD'S Passover.
 </Verse>
 </Cite>

 <Cite cite="Deut. 16:5-6">
 <Verse verse="5">
 <P b="1" u="1">Thou mayest not</P> <P ss="1" b="1">sacrifice the Passover</P> <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">within any of thy gates</P>, which the LORD thy God giveth thee.
 </Verse>

 <Verse verse="6">
 <P b="1">But at the place which the LORD thy God shall choose to place his name in</P>, there thou shalt sacrifice the Passover at even, at the going down of the sun, at the season that thou camest forth out of Egypt.
 </Verse>
 </Cite>

 <Paragraph>
 As we see, the Jewish Passover of our times is a very poor caricature of the one that Moses instituted by God’s command. Almost everything that they do today has been invented by the rabbis and not by God as told to Moses. Can this be God’s religion? <P ss="1" b="1">Who gave the leaders and rabbis permission to modify the commands of God? Why are they doing the same thing as the Pope: Inventing a religion and imposing it dogmatically without Scriptural support?</P>
 </Paragraph>

 <Section title="Sins were cleansed by sacrificial lambs. How can they purify themselves if there are no sacrifices today?">
<Paragraph>
Another thing happens with today’s Jewish religion. Following God, Moses established that sins were to be cleansed with the sacrifice of lambs that were symbols, a demonstration of faith in what was to come. But now the Jewish religion does not sacrifice lambs nor accept the Lamb of God. Therefore, the sins of the believers are not cleansed, or they pretend to “cleanse” their sins in a way that God through Moses did not establish, but rather was invented by a rabbi or group of rabbis without divine authorization. To whom was given or who usurped the divine authority to change what God had established? <P ss="1" b="1">They are doing what the Popes do; modify at whim what God instituted</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
Jesus was killed at the hour of the sacrifice of the Passover lamb, on the afternoon before the night when the Passover was eaten. Since the true Passover was Jesus, the ritual portion of this event has fallen into disuse.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
God is all powerful. <P ss="1" b="1">If Jesus was not the true Passover, if He had not been the true Lamb of God who takes away once and forever the sins of all who accept his pardon</P>, <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">God would not have permitted the cessation of the Temple sacrifices</P>.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
If the only way that God had established for the cleansing of our sins was the sacrificing of lambs in the Temple, and if the Temple no longer existed for the sacrificing of lambs, then how would there be pardon for the sins of the Jews who died from the time when the Temple was destroyed until now? And how would their sins be forgiven today? With what authority has a new way of obtaining cleansing for sins be established, if any new way has been established? And if no new way has been established, what is the destiny of sinners who are Jewish?
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
<P b="1">All of this is screaming into the ears of every Jew who does not close his ears</P>, that the Temple sacrifices were a simple symbol of the future sacrifice of Jesus Christ on the cross. This is why that once the true sacrifice of the true Lamb of God occurred, there is no longer any need for the Temple nor for the sacrifices of lambs. For this reason the Temple that was destroyed has never been rebuilt in about 2000 years.
</Paragraph>

<Paragraph>
In chapter 16 of the book of Leviticus we see that during Yom Kippur some sacrifices had to be made according to the order of Moses by mandate of God, to get forgiveness. Who authorizes not to sacrifice now, but keep saying that it is the day of forgiveness?
</Paragraph>
 </Section>

 <Section title="The actual Judaism is not a divine Mosaic religion, but a non-divine rabbinical religion.">

 </Section>

 <Section title="Summary of Chapter 6">
 <Paragraph>
 Should a sincere worshiper of God change His laws without divine permission? Certainly not. This is what Judaism has done with the laws that God set forth through Moses. The immense majority of believers in God, including Christians, ignores the laws of God and changes the commandments. Examples in Christianity include the changes of the Sabbath and the worship of images; examples in Judaism occur in the Passover celebrated outside of Jerusalem and the pardon of sins without the sacrifice of lambs.
 </Paragraph>

 <Paragraph>
 Jesus Christ had to die on the same day as the sacrifice of the Passover lamb. If Jesus had not been the true Lamb of God that cleanses once and for all the sins of those who accept His pardon,
 <P ss="1" b="1" u="1">God would not have permitted cessation of the Temple sacrifices</P>. This shouts in the ears of all who do not cover them that Jesus Christ is the Messiah.
 </Paragraph>
 </Section>
</Chapter>
